<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>ThreeFold - grid</title>
	<subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
	<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/categories/grid/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/categories/grid/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How ThreeFold Can Truly Decentralize Blockchain</title>
		<published>2021-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-10-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/decentralize-blockchain/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/decentralize-blockchain/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The topic of decentralization is commonly tied to blockchain and cryptocurrencies. Blockchain doesn’t store any of its information in a central location, rather it is copied and spread across a network of computers. And the most popular name in the blockchain space, Bitcoin, was intended as an alternative payment system free of central control.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But many blockchains are facing the same challenge: How can they escape the monopolies of centralized cloud providers for their own workloads, as well as for the dApps built on top of them? The key question is, is a blockchain truly decentralized if it is being hosted on a centralized solution? We say: no.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example to illustrate this challenge is the fact that up to 60% of Ethereum (the world’s second most-popular blockchain) nodes run on centralized cloud providers and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;aws.amazon.com&#x2F;blockchain&#x2F;&quot;&gt;25% of them run on Amazon Web Services (AWS)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the topic is being addressed, it isn’t being solved at scale. The good news is that ThreeFold can play a large part in solving it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-should-blockchains-make-this-move&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#why-should-blockchains-make-this-move&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: why-should-blockchains-make-this-move&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Why should blockchains make this move?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The blockchain movement, as mentioned, is very heavily tied to the movement around decentralization. Cryptocurrencies represent the move away from centralized banks as the authorities and gatekeepers around money – just as ThreeFold and similar projects represent the move away from centralized clouds as the authorities and gatekeepers around data. The thing is, if blockchains are to rely on centralized cloud for hosting, they aren’t truly embodying decentralization.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understandably, many blockchains have chosen centralized cloud providers in the past because there wasn’t much of an alternative. But now, the Decentralized Cloud (DeCloud) movement has changed all of that.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is how some specific audiences can benefit:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-node-operators&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#for-node-operators&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: for-node-operators&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;For Node Operators&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any full node or validator node can run on ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Peer-to-Peer (P2P) Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, making that particular Blockchain even more community-owned, and more decentralized from an IT&#x2F;cloud level. Any node operator can choose to run their nodes from any farmer location on the ThreeFold Grid, totally &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;what_is_peer_to_peer&#x2F;&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; between the chosen farmer and the node operator. The deployed workloads are computed in a P2P manner, no middle party involved.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;for-dapp-developers&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#for-dapp-developers&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: for-dapp-developers&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;For dApp Developers&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Web3&#x2F;Blockchain developers can use ThreeFold’s P2P Cloud - offering both compute and storage - to build and power their applications in a truly decentralized cloud infrastructure, both blockchain-native and cloud-native. A strong advantage here is that developers have the ability to leverage Kubernetes, Docker, S3, and other cloud-native tools (all compatible &#x2F; integrated with the ThreeFold) to power and optimize their data processing capabilities, as well as the overall functionality of their dApps. But the sweet spot is that it is deployed on a decentralized IT infrastructure, close to where users would be located.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-why-choose-threefold-over-other-decloud-projects&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#but-why-choose-threefold-over-other-decloud-projects&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: but-why-choose-threefold-over-other-decloud-projects&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;But why choose ThreeFold over other DeCloud projects?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There may be bigger names in the space, but ThreeFold’s technology and offerings are much more comprehensive than the rest. ThreeFold provides decentralized storage, compute, and network all under one roof (whereas most other projects offer only one of the three) and as mentioned, we have created an environment for developers which is highly-compatible to the developer tools and solutions they use today. Further, ThreeFold is building new infrastructure &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;an_intro_to_the_threefold_grid&#x2F;&quot;&gt;from the ground up&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (rather than relying on extra space in data centers) and the technology is truly peer-to-peer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We already have &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;partners&#x2F;blockchain&quot;&gt;a number of partners in the space&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; who recognize these advantages.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any blockchain protocol or dApp, whether operating DeFi, NFTs, DEXs, etc, will at some point need to leverage the power of the decentralized cloud and escape from centralized cloud providers. We’re seeing some of that adoption from a decentralized storage side with IPFS, which has been adopted by many dApps, and others – but as a developer, you will have to think twice, not just about where your&#x2F;your users’ data is being stored, but also about how (and where) your app is computed and powered.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Participate now in our quest to fully decentralize the Internet by &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;becoming a node&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on our grid or &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;buying TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Why Anyone Should Consider Becoming A (ThreeFold) Farmer</title>
		<published>2020-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/why-become-a-farmer/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/why-become-a-farmer/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Foundation is changing the way how &quot;we&quot; as a whole approach the internet and its underlying technology. We believe building the internet back from the ground up is the only way to dismantle the monster it has grown into – a polluting greed-machine that allows people’s data to be abused for money all while just being accessible to just half of the earth’s inhabitants.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And the best part is, you can have a part in the global shift towards a more sustainable, inclusive, and respectful internet by becoming a ThreeFold Farmer.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-are-farmers&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#so-what-are-farmers&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: so-what-are-farmers&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;So what are farmers?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put: Farmers are people that add capacity to the ThreeFold Grid for anyone to use.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-this-capacity&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#what-is-this-capacity&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: what-is-this-capacity&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;What is this “capacity”?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capacity is the raw building blocks needed for any internet grid: CPU (processors), Hard Drives, Solid-state drives, memory, etc. Capacity can then be rented by developers and engineers that would like to run their applications on the ThreeFold Grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-in-it-for-me&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#what-is-in-it-for-me&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: what-is-in-it-for-me&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;What is in it for me?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in the previous paragraph, capacity is rented. This means people that put capacity on the ThreeFold Grid are getting paid by anybody that uses their capacity. But there is more, ThreeFold also incentivizes farmers to add capacity by giving them tokens simply for adding the capacity to the ThreeFold Grid. The amount they receive depends on the specifications of the capacity they put online (how much, how powerful, etc). These tokens are then gradually released over the course of 60 months. So in short, you get paid to do this.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-else&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#what-else&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: what-else&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;What else?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capacity for the ThreeFold Grid can be added in all shapes and sizes. It could be a small box no larger than a modem that you put in your office or home, or could be a fully-fledged data center node. The idea is that the grid becomes spread out as much as it can be, as this has some huge benefits for all users and the environment.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less power waste: Less energy is needed to cool all these smaller nodes that are far away from each other, than putting the same resources in a giant room together and having them sit on top off, and beside each other (this is what happens now in large scale data centers).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Less bandwidth waste: The closer the capacity is to the end-user, the less unnecessary miles it has to travel. (e.g. a text message in a messaging app might travel from the Netherlands to a data center in America to then forward it to the person living down the street). When concentrating on decentralization and having nodes everywhere in the world this problem resolves itself. And data will take the shortest route possible.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More Privacy: This decentralized approach makes it so that there is no “all-seeing eye” within the network – unlike the current setup where tech giants basically own all their users’ data by putting it in their own data centers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More Accessibility: Due to the fact that these resources can be added in small form-factors, it makes it possible to now put internet resources anywhere in the world where there’s a network to plug into (cables in the ground). And this makes it that now people that have limited-to-no funds have access to what the UN declared a human right: the internet. ut more than that, education, connection, entertainment, all the internet brought the western world over the past decade.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To find out more about how you can become a farmer, please visit ThreeFold’s website &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.threefold.io&quot;&gt;www.threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;wiki&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or register to for first access to our next batch of 3Node here: &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;pre-register.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;pre-register.threefold.io&#x2F;&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. We are currently collecting interest for all types of nodes that anyone can host in their home, office, or anywhere else with a power outlet and internet connection. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Decentralizing the Internet</title>
		<published>2019-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-08-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/decentralizing-the-internet/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/decentralizing-the-internet/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;decentralization&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#decentralization&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: decentralization&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Decentralization&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1989, the Internet changed the world as we know it with the introduction of the World Wide Web. With time the Internet empowered people to share information in a decentralized way. Shortly after, big companies like Facebook, Google, and Apple emerged, providing many solutions that revolutionized the way we live. The “sharing economy” has grown exponentially over the last 5-10 years. This is thanks to a more simplified information flow and well-developed technology, which:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enables a much easier integration of independent players into the sharing economy.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Eliminates the need for extensive management and structure of marketplace operators.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
We are entering a flat-structure economy. An economy where fewer managerial levels are needed for the system to function. New technologies such as blockchain and the Internet of Things facilitate this ongoing trend. Participants can now interact on a peer-to-peer basis, forming marketplaces and organizations according to pre-agreed, programmed contracts.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-current-internet-is-centralized&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#the-current-internet-is-centralized&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: the-current-internet-is-centralized&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;The current Internet is centralized&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the growth in popularity for decentralized systems, organizations, and currencies, the Internet remains centralized. The centralization within the Internet industry brought many barriers to entry. Indeed, to compete in the highly competitive market of Internet capacity dominated by big IT companies, massive investment, and IT development are needed.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
But what is really scary is that the current industry exploits the market tremendously. Data is officially the most valuable asset on earth for a few years, and about 20 companies rule over more than 80% of the cloud industry. In other words - these companies together have more than 80% of the world’s information. In recent years, we noticed the dangers that can arise with the wrong intentions within the data industry with the ‘Cambridge Analytica Scandal’, also highlighted in the movie &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=iX8GxLP1FHo&quot;&gt;‘The Great Hack’.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold has been developing technology that allows the decentralization of the Internet infrastructure - removing the need for data centers, and allowing anyone to take part in the Internet capacity market. Adding capacity to the ThreeFold Grid (TF Grid) makes you a ThreeFold Farmer (TF Farmer). The more decentralized the Internet gets, the more secure and effective it will become. The already is the largest grid of compute and storage in the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-participate&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#how-to-participate&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: how-to-participate&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;How To Participate&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of becoming a ThreeFold Farmer is very straightforward. Anyone can join the ThreeFold Grid by downloading the ThreeFold Zero-OS onto their nodes and connecting them to the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
By doing this you will become an operator of a “micro data center” and with that earn ThreeFold Tokens. With or without experience in the field, anyone can become a ThreeFold Farmer. By becoming a ThreeFold Farmer, you empower a new neutral Internet that belongs to humanity - not corporations.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You can build your server (3node) and configure it, but also options for people with less technical knowledge are available. Please see &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;pre-register.threefold.io&quot;&gt;pre-register.threefold.io&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to see how easy it is for anyone to become a ThreeFold Farmer.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Blog written in 2019, updated January 2021.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Solving the Blockchain Dilemma</title>
		<published>2018-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2018-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/blockchain-dilemma/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/blockchain-dilemma/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;introduction&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#introduction&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: introduction&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Introduction&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockchain technology has the power to change the world of IT. There are a huge number of new initiatives using blockchain technology around the world, with countless use cases.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In general, there are two types of blockchains: proof of work blockchains and proof of stake blockchains. They are consensus algorithms on how transactions are verified and added to the ledger (forever, as blockchains provide an immutable record of events). More on these two types of blockchains below.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;blockchain-basics&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#blockchain-basics&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: blockchain-basics&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Blockchain Basics&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A blockchain is, as the word says, a chain of blocks of information. These “blocks” contain information on transactions. For instance transactions like the transfer of value of a digital currency (token) from wallet A to wallet B. The “chain” aspect comes when part of the information is stored in a block as a link to the previous block (a unique number). This is a very simple representation of what a blockchain is.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;private-permissioned-or-public-blockchains&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#private-permissioned-or-public-blockchains&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: private-permissioned-or-public-blockchains&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Private, Permissioned or Public Blockchains&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complexity around a blockchain comes from how the blockchain software is run. The software can run in two different ways: a small (or large) number of nodes controlled by one single entity (private blockchain) a person or a company, or a large (or small) number of nodes controlled by multiple entities (public) that do not know each other and where anyone interested to run a blockchain node can join.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
By running blockchain software under the supervision of one entity (private, centralized) you can quite easily make sure the information stored in the blockchain (transactions) are not tempered with by only operating a small number of nodes and deploying them in very safe physical locations (private data-centers, vaults, basements of offices, etc). A private blockchain does not allow unknown entities to join and run the blockchain software.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
A permissioned blockchain is operated by known entities such as stakeholders of a given industry. It is a mix of both private and public blockchains. In this type of blockchain network, a participant may not need permission to join the network but needs permission to transact with another network participant.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
A public blockchain allows anyone to join the blockchain operation and create a new blockchain node. The blockchain is run by multiple entities (decentralized, public) that have no relationship nor knowledge about each other 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
For these three types of blockchains, there are different mechanisms to protect and guarantee the validity of transactions and make them tamper-proof.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;private-data-and-anonymous-or-pseudo-anonymous-data&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#private-data-and-anonymous-or-pseudo-anonymous-data&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: private-data-and-anonymous-or-pseudo-anonymous-data&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Private Data and Anonymous or Pseudo-Anonymous Data?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For private blockchains, it is straightforward to see that all data that is stored on private blockchains is private and creates 100% anonymity for its users. The only entity or person that has access to information stored on the blockchain is the blockchain operator. This is comparable to how a bank operates. The bank knows everything about all of its customers and the customers only know about themselves - the non-bank customers do not know a thing.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
On a public blockchain, people can join and operate a blockchain node on which all information of that blockchain is stored. While private blockchains get their security from putting their blockchain nodes in secure buildings operated by trusted people a public blockchain achieves its security from having a large number of nodes that have the same data replicated over and over. A consensus algorithm is required in order to accept new data (new blocks) to the chain.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;consensus-protocols-for-public-blockchains&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#consensus-protocols-for-public-blockchains&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: consensus-protocols-for-public-blockchains&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Consensus Protocols for Public Blockchains&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main consensus protocols used today are Proof-of-Work and Proof-of-Stake.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;proof-of-work-high-cost-in-compute-and-energy&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#proof-of-work-high-cost-in-compute-and-energy&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: proof-of-work-high-cost-in-compute-and-energy&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Proof of Work (High Cost in Compute and Energy)&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The proof of work consensus protocol is best explained as a race. The consensus is achieved by having all participating nodes solve a puzzle. The puzzle is a one-way translation of an amount of information consisting of the following items:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All the data that present the transactions in the block - all the data is known by all participating nodes&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The number of the previous block. Remember a blockchain links blocks of information together.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A (variable) number. This number is the part that can be changed.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The “work” is done by changing the variable number and see what the translation of all data brings. The translation of all this data is a new number, and the requirement is that that number needs to be smaller than what is known as the “difficulty level”. The difficulty level number has a fixed amount of numbers but when the first digits of the number are zero the overall number is lower. So a higher difficulty is built by having a number that has more zeros at the start in the difficulty number.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Once the block is completed, all nodes will get the complete block of transactional data, everyone knows the previous block number and will start to change the variable number to get output from the puzzle algorithms comparing it to the required difficulty level.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The node that will find the number first will announce that it has found a solution matching the required difficulty level and the variable number of shared with all nodes in the network to verify that his solution is correct. If a large portion of the nodes has verified the solution to be valid the solution is accepted and the block is added to the chain because consensus is reached.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;proof-of-block-stake-low-cost-in-compute-and-energy&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#proof-of-block-stake-low-cost-in-compute-and-energy&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: proof-of-block-stake-low-cost-in-compute-and-energy&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Proof of (Block) Stake (Low Cost in Compute and Energy)&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With proof of stake consensus algorithms, the consensus algorithm does not solve puzzles in a race to be the first. The first step is to identify and allow a certain number of nodes to be part of the blockchain. This is called a permissioned blockchain because you need to have permission to partake. This permission is given by distributing stakes.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Proof of Stake consensus mechanism is solving a puzzle, but the puzzle contains only static elements - not variables - based on different characteristics:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The block number&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The content (part) of blocks a long time ago (&amp;gt;2000 blocks)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The transaction number (between the first and the last transaction) in the block of the stake transfer transaction all participating nodes needs to&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The current timestamp
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
All these numbers are fixed but the time stamp and every node in the block stake blockchain will solve this puzzle every second until the output of this puzzle matches the required difficulty level. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
To make sure the one node that has solved the puzzle to match the difficulty level cannot introduce information in the block which allows him to tamper with the next blocks this node cannot use his used stake for a period amount of time for creating new blocks.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The fact that the puzzle-solving includes historic block data and once a node is assigned to create the block and put it on a chain will not be able to use that block state for a period of time makes it very costly to try to tamper with the content of the block (and the next blocks). &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-blockchain-dilemma-problem&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#the-blockchain-dilemma-problem&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: the-blockchain-dilemma-problem&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;The Blockchain Dilemma Problem&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public and private blockchains have their specific advantages and disadvantages and are very good for specific use cases - but not all. If we list the specifics of both we end up with a table like this:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
| * | Public Blockchains | Private Blockchains |
|—|—|—|
| Security | Provided by having a large number of nodes running it | Provided by having them in secure controlled places | 
| People | Build, managed and controlled by unknown people | Build, managed, and controlled by known people |&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
| Speed | Slow by design - all data needs to be copied to all of them | Fast(er) and more efficient by design - a smaller number of copies of the blockchain data |&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
So what if we want to have a secure, performant, and easy to manage blockchain solution?  This is not what can be delivered by either type of blockchains.  We have to create a new type of blockchain that combines the best of both worlds and delivers.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The key element in finding a solution for this problem is to take the human element out of it.  The fact that when you deploy blockchains solutions in locations without human intervention means that you need to create a different deployment mechanism that takes out people touching code, compiling code, deploying code, and in the end operating the machine in which the code runs.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
A way to get around the trusted people problem is to select a platform on which software can be downloaded, compiled, installed, and operated without human intervention.  Such a platform is a unique platform that has not been developed and launched. Such a platform would have to have the following characteristics. To make this system work and solve the blockchain dilemma we need to have three components working together in an orchestrated way.  The three elements are:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zero-OS&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: A (simple) operating system that does not allow local and remote logins - a closed operating system that receives instructions to launch or kill applications.  This operating system  needs to be stateless to keep as simple as possible: &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3Bot&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: A virtual system administrator that is able to perform system administration tasks to make the system operate, self-heal and execute instructions from authenticated and authorized sources.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zero-Chain&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: A ledger or database to store information with regards to authentication, operational and financial transactions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This system architecture allows for authenticated and trusted virtual system administrators to download, compile and deploy software on a grid of secure Zero-OS nodes with an immutable ledger that records all transactions, operational and financial. This presents a platform on which a public (permissioned) blockchain can be run securely without requiring trusted people to operate the nodes. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In such architecture, we can build and deploy a high-performance secure blockchain which are the combined benefits of a public and private blockchain.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
