<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>ThreeFold - data</title>
	<subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
	<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/tags/data/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/tags/data/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The Internet is Moving to the Edge</title>
		<published>2022-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/internet-at-the-edge/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/internet-at-the-edge/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;With new devices being connected every day and emerging technologies like the Internet of Things (IoT), the metaverse and Web 3 gaining popularity, the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cbre.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;insights&#x2F;reports&#x2F;north-america-data-center-trends-h2-2021&quot;&gt;demand&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for Internet capacity is booming. Already, these developments are shifting the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.securityinfowatch.com&#x2F;perimeter-security&#x2F;physical-hardening&#x2F;article&#x2F;21263002&#x2F;real-words-or-buzzwords-edge-cloud-and-the-evolving-internet&quot;&gt;Internet’s “center of gravity”&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from its core to the edges in order to keep up with the growing demand. In an increasingly interconnected world, centralized cloud architectures are proving to be &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.forbes.com&#x2F;sites&#x2F;forbestechcouncil&#x2F;2022&#x2F;03&#x2F;25&#x2F;demystifying-edge-technology&#x2F;&quot;&gt;bottlenecks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; hindering future growth.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some interesting numbers to emphasize the explosive growth of connected devices and the impending data explosion:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Back in 2018, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.securityinfowatch.com&#x2F;perimeter-security&#x2F;physical-hardening&#x2F;article&#x2F;21263002&#x2F;real-words-or-buzzwords-edge-cloud-and-the-evolving-internet&quot;&gt;90% of global data creation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; took place within the two previous years.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 2022, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.securityinfowatch.com&#x2F;perimeter-security&#x2F;physical-hardening&#x2F;article&#x2F;21263002&#x2F;real-words-or-buzzwords-edge-cloud-and-the-evolving-internet&quot;&gt;4.95 billion people&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are using the Internet and about &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.securityinfowatch.com&#x2F;perimeter-security&#x2F;physical-hardening&#x2F;article&#x2F;21263002&#x2F;real-words-or-buzzwords-edge-cloud-and-the-evolving-internet&quot;&gt;2.5 quintillion bytes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of data are created on a daily basis.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About 2 billion computers, 15 billion mobile devices and more than 22 billion IoT devices are &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.securityinfowatch.com&#x2F;perimeter-security&#x2F;physical-hardening&#x2F;article&#x2F;21263002&#x2F;real-words-or-buzzwords-edge-cloud-and-the-evolving-internet&quot;&gt;active worldwide&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on a daily basis.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By 2025, more than &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cisco.com&#x2F;c&#x2F;en&#x2F;us&#x2F;solutions&#x2F;executive-perspectives&#x2F;annual-internet-report&#x2F;index.html&quot;&gt;1 billion people&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.statista.com&#x2F;statistics&#x2F;471264&#x2F;iot-number-of-connected-devices-worldwide&#x2F;#:%7E:text=Internet%20of%20Things%20%2D%20number%20of%20connected%20devices%20worldwide%202015%2D2025&amp;amp;text=By%202025%2C%20forecasts%20suggest%20that,IoT%20installed%20base%20in%202019.&quot;&gt;75 billion IoT devices&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are expected to join the Internet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And yet, the expansion of Internet capacity still largely occurs in the same centralized and inefficient way. The client-server model of hyperscale data centers is unable to meet this rapidly growing demand due to high building and operational costs to fulfill bandwidth, performance and cybersecurity requirements. As data centers are primarily built in the US, China and Europe, emerging countries have to be connected via sea cables which makes the model’s limitations particularly severe for these countries. And even in countries where many data centers are located, they are built in regions where land and electricity are as cheap as possible. Consequently, the bulk of data centers is still &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.securityinfowatch.com&#x2F;perimeter-security&#x2F;physical-hardening&#x2F;article&#x2F;21263002&#x2F;real-words-or-buzzwords-edge-cloud-and-the-evolving-internet&quot;&gt;far away&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from where the majority of users and connected devices reside, and where huge amounts of data are generated that require processing – resulting in a &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;threefold__grid_valuation?id=what39s-the-potential-of-the-threefold-grid&quot;&gt;weak distribution&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of Internet capacity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;About &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.seagate.com&#x2F;files&#x2F;www-content&#x2F;our-story&#x2F;rethink-data&#x2F;files&#x2F;Rethink_Data_Report_2020.pdf&quot;&gt;175 Zettabytes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of data will be created by 2025, as our economy becomes increasingly digital and data driven. And this amount of data needs to be captured, stored and activated in a secure, efficient and high-performing way. So, the aforementioned technological use cases will not only &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.cbre.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;insights&#x2F;reports&#x2F;north-america-data-center-trends-h2-2021&quot;&gt;accelerate the demand&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for Internet capacity but also require edge capabilities, such as low latencies, in order to run and scale successfully. In fact, the centralized data center model poses one of the biggest obstacles to the success and spread of the Internet of Things and related applications. This will have to change. Actually, industry experts &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.i-scoop.eu&#x2F;edge-computing-explained&#x2F;&quot;&gt;expect 75%&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of data to be processed outside of the traditional data center or cloud model by 2025.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-rise-of-edge-computing&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#the-rise-of-edge-computing&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: the-rise-of-edge-computing&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;The rise of edge computing&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Computing needs to be pushed from centralized data centers to the edge to support the massive data consumption coupled to the rise of connected devices and emerging technologies. For instance, as more and more home appliances and devices are getting interconnected through the IoT economy, the amount of real-time data generated within our homes on a daily basis is rapidly expanding. Edge computing &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.i-scoop.eu&#x2F;edge-computing-explained&#x2F;&quot;&gt;tackles the shortcomings&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the centralized model in terms of bandwidth, latency and autonomy. It enables applications and solutions to be hosted closer to where their data is being produced and consumed, thereby allowing for low latencies, rapid data processing and real-time decisions. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The industry analyst company &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.idc.com&#x2F;getdoc.jsp?containerId=prUS48772522&quot;&gt;IDC estimates&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; the global spending on edge computing to increase by 14.8% compared to 2021 – amounting to roughly $176 billion in 2022. By 2025, this number is predicted to reach about $274 billion.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea of edge computing’s ability to process data on-site is simple enough. Nevertheless, edge computing fails to deliver on its promise as it still remains somewhat centralized today. Granted, so-called edge data centers are &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;stlpartners.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;edge-computing&#x2F;edge-data-centres&#x2F;&quot;&gt;closer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to where the data is being consumed than hyperscale data centers. But while they do provide an improvement from traditional data centers, they are not able to provide &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.thefastmode.com&#x2F;expert-opinion&#x2F;23002-what-are-various-types-of-edge-computing-that-exist-today&quot;&gt;far-edge&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; capabilities, i.e. moving as close to the user and point of data creation as possible. They are simply smaller types of data centers that are still operated in a centralized manner, require the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;connectorsupplier.com&#x2F;how-the-rise-of-edge-computing-will-reshape-the-data-center-landscape&#x2F;&quot;&gt;same infrastructure elements&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as centralized data centers, and usually &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.techtarget.com&#x2F;searchdatacenter&#x2F;definition&#x2F;edge-data-center&quot;&gt;rely&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on bigger, central data centers. Quite edgy isn’t it?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As the need for Internet capacity – specifically at the edge – is rapidly intensifying, a new approach to Internet infrastructure is clearly needed. The Web 3 movement created a spur of interest across industries due to its promise to decentralize the Internet and cloud as we know it. Future data will be generated at the edge of the network and Internet which certainly requires an &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.forbes.com&#x2F;sites&#x2F;forbestechcouncil&#x2F;2022&#x2F;03&#x2F;25&#x2F;demystifying-edge-technology&#x2F;&quot;&gt;architectural shift&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; away from the current model.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;realizing-an-interconnected-future&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#realizing-an-interconnected-future&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: realizing-an-interconnected-future&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Realizing an interconnected future&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ironically, decades after the spark of the open-source peer-to-peer Internet movement was steamrolled by large tech companies and governments eager to centralize the global Internet, we seem to enter an era of decentralization again. There’s no doubt that large tech companies did bring a lot of innovation to our global Internet and cloud stack. Technically though, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;p2p_web3&#x2F;&quot;&gt;peer-to-peer&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; systems have always been the most scalable option. Moreover, open-source architectures have built a strong reputation for providing high levels of security and flexibility. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a peer-to-peer model, people and devices are able to exchange directly, without intermediaries or servers in the middle – leading to a more energy-efficient, scalable and flexible paradigm that can expand on-demand. And undoubtedly, open-source will play a &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;news.crunchbase.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;edge-computing-said-quissal-zededa&#x2F;&quot;&gt;key role&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; in edge computing by simplifying and enhancing the building and deployment of software at the edge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By leveraging open-source and peer-to-peer technologies, ThreeFold has come up with an Internet infrastructure that is capable of far-edge computing. ThreeFold offers a powerful set of &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;building_a_new_internet_from_the_ground_up_3&#x2F;&quot;&gt;compute primitives&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that provide the agility to create and deploy containers, Virtual Machines (VMs) and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__zkube?id=zkube&quot;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; environments at the edge. Having integrated all leading industry-standard tools, ThreeFold’s solution allows for a seamless migration of any digital workload, making ThreeFold the ideal infrastructure for edge workloads. And all data produced by these workloads can be stored in a way that is ultra safe, highly reliable and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;qsss&#x2F;threefold__qsss_home?id=quantum-safe-storage-system&quot;&gt;unbreakable&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Combined with end-to-end encrypted peer-to-peer &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;technology&#x2F;threefold__planetary_network?id=planetary-network&quot;&gt;networking&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, applications can be hosted closer to where the data is being consumed – representing the ideal underlying layer for IoT networks, blockchain-based workloads and more to run and scale at the edge seamlessly, efficiently and privately.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shift towards the edge is inevitable. ThreeFold is the first full-stack, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;coincheckup.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold-is-the-decentralized-web-the-future-of-the-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;decentralized&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure in the world that combines compute in the form of highly-optimized containers, storage and network capacity in an all-in-one solution. With  more than &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;81 Petabytes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of capacity distributed across thousands of 3Nodes and 76 countries as well as &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;connecting_the_dots&#x2F;&quot;&gt;plans&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; to sponsor the expansion of the Internet to developing regions, ThreeFold is the foundation for a thriving interconnected future that is secure, borderless and at the edge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;what_is_farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Expand the new Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by setting up a 3Node at your home or office.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help us &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;connecting_the_dots&#x2F;&quot;&gt;connect the dots&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and accelerate our far-edge capabilities.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join our global &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; today.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The Internet that connects us also manipulates us. In search of a better future.</title>
		<published>2022-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-04-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/in-search-of-a-better-internet/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/in-search-of-a-better-internet/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Internet is one of humanity’s &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;coincodex.com&#x2F;article&#x2F;14083&#x2F;threefold-host-the-cloud-at-your-house&#x2F;&quot;&gt;greatest inventions&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. In its early days, it used to be &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;theconversation.com&#x2F;web-3-0-the-decentralised-web-promises-to-make-the-internet-free-again-113139&quot;&gt;free and decentralized&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by nature. No single entity was able to control access to the web as it was built on the foundation of a peer-to-peer network of nodes owned by developers and researchers. Until the dot-com era. Throughout the early 2000s, large corporations took over the web. New platforms like YouTube and MySpace were launched and new infrastructure needed to be built at an extreme pace, starting the data revolution and changing the digital landscape forever. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twenty years down the line, the Internet’s architecture has become highly centralized – owned by a handful of large corporations that act as the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.newyorker.com&#x2F;magazine&#x2F;2017&#x2F;08&#x2F;28&#x2F;who-owns-the-internet&quot;&gt;gatekeepers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of our digital world. What was once an open and free platform accessible to anyone has long since built up barriers and lost its neutrality. Users are trapped in a cyberspace that exploits their personal data and allows censorship, hate speech, disinformation and political targeting to thrive. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;going-down-the-rabbit-hole&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#going-down-the-rabbit-hole&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: going-down-the-rabbit-hole&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Going down the Rabbit Hole&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Wall Street Journal’s &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wsj.com&#x2F;articles&#x2F;the-facebook-files-11631713039&quot;&gt;investigation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; “The Facebook Files” and The New York Times’ audio series “&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.nytimes.com&#x2F;2020&#x2F;04&#x2F;22&#x2F;podcasts&#x2F;rabbit-hole-prologue.html&quot;&gt;Rabbit Hole&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;” are only some of the latest examples that depict the shocking impacts of the manipulation, mental health problems, and extremism that social media algorithms are fuelling. Nevertheless, these incidents are only a glimpse into all the ways we’re being affected and influenced about the way we see the world – by the tech giants and their algorithms. Tech giants like Google and Facebook have been surrounded by a constant stream of data privacy &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.wired.com&#x2F;story&#x2F;should-big-tech-own-our-personal-data&#x2F;&quot;&gt;scandals&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; as more and more whistleblowers expose their misconduct. However, there are plenty of other, hidden players using the tools and algorithms of social media platforms for their own agendas.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;filmthreat.com&#x2F;features&#x2F;4-thought-provoking-movies-on-digital-privacy-and-security&#x2F;&quot;&gt;The Great Hack and the Social Dilemma&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are great documentaries that shed light on how the Internet as we know it became compromised. They depict how algorithms are used to mine user data, control information feeds and manipulate our digital experiences. The &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.politico.eu&#x2F;article&#x2F;cambridge-analytica-chris-wylie-brexit-trump-britain-data-protection-privacy-facebook&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Trump Election and the Brexit vote&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; were heavily influenced by private companies like &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theguardian.com&#x2F;news&#x2F;series&#x2F;cambridge-analytica-files&quot;&gt;Cambridge Analytica&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that manipulated mass audiences through social media.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By purchasing thousands of personal data points collected by social media platforms and analyzing them, companies like Cambridge Analytica are able to not only predict but influence the behaviour of each and everyone of us. Data collection and analysis to such an extent allow these companies to craft and push perfectly targeted messages to users in a way that’s optimized to sway their opinions in favour of whatever agenda they have.  &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;can-a-neutral-and-free-internet-still-exist&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#can-a-neutral-and-free-internet-still-exist&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: can-a-neutral-and-free-internet-still-exist&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Can a neutral and free Internet still exist?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On 24th of March 2022, the European Parliament and Council negotiators agreed upon the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;variety.com&#x2F;2022&#x2F;digital&#x2F;global&#x2F;facebook-google-amazon-apple-digital-market-act-europe-regulation-1235214516&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Digital Markets Act&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (DMA). It seeks to give users more choice by demanding the most popular apps to open up and interoperate with smaller apps. Moreover, the act aims to ensure a fairer market competition by prohibiting certain gatekeeper practices like self-preferencing and targeted advertising. This set of new EU regulations is likely to impact the daily business of tech giants significantly once it becomes law. While the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.europarl.europa.eu&#x2F;news&#x2F;en&#x2F;press-room&#x2F;20220315IPR25504&#x2F;deal-on-digital-markets-act-ensuring-fair-competition-and-more-choice-for-users&quot;&gt;DMA&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; promises to mitigate some of the issues discussed, it is doubtful that the act will be enough to fundamentally change the current system. This is a step in the right direction, but much more needs to be done.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet has become our digital home. It’s impacting our lives in many ways by creating new opportunities, and changing how we communicate and connect. Therefore, it is crucial to restore the Internet’s neutrality to ensure a fair and equal environment. We need an Internet where we can rely on data security and privacy. An Internet where we’re empowered to truly and completely have ownership of and control of our own data. An Internet that empowers us with digital sovereignty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet used to be a free movement of culture and the Web. It started with an open-source and peer-to-peer vision to connect people. And while Web 3.0 projects are looking to liberalize the Internet as we know it, most of them still rely on centralized Web 2.0 infrastructure to some degree. The world needs better, holistic solutions. ThreeFold is &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;realizing_the_promise&#x2F;&quot;&gt;realizing the initial vision and promise&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of the Internet as an open-source, peer-to-peer planetary mesh network of nodes owned by humanity. It’s a 100% open-source and community-driven project that builds the critical, neutral infrastructure for a decentralized world – one that is built and owned by the people. With ThreeFold, individuals and organizations are empowered to store their data and run their applications on a peer-to-peer network of nodes in a way that ensures their data will not be manipulated, hacked or lost. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Powered by a global community, ThreeFold is the world’s largest peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure with a few thousand 3Nodes connected from 74 countries and the neutral foundation for &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;medium.com&#x2F;authority-magazine&#x2F;the-future-is-now-kristoff-de-spiegeleer-of-threefold-on-how-their-technological-innovation-will-7acc0e51c365&quot;&gt;any current and future IT workload&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. ThreeFold is now on the verge of opening up a new Internet era free from censorship, user tracking and privacy breaches. And anyone can participate in ThreeFold’s model by building or buying a 3Node, and connecting Internet capacity from their home or office – creating a fully &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;coincheckup.com&#x2F;blog&#x2F;threefold-is-the-decentralized-web-the-future-of-the-internet&#x2F;&quot;&gt;decentralized Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join the ThreeFold &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; today and drive a new Internet era.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Break free from big tech and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;what_is_farming&#x2F;&quot;&gt;be the Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by setting up a 3Node at your home.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Help us &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;connecting_the_dots&#x2F;&quot;&gt;connect the dots&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Can a &#x27;Democratized&#x27; Internet exist in times of a Cyber War?</title>
		<published>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/cyberwar/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/cyberwar/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On February 24 2022, Russia launched a large-scale military invasion and attack on Ukraine. In the days since the invasion began, the war has been fought not only on the ground and in the air, but also in the digital realm.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyber warfare is nothing new, especially in Russia and Eastern Europe. “In the relatively short and rapidly evolving history of cyber conflict, perhaps nothing has been established with greater certainty and more widely accepted than the idea that Russia has significant cyber capabilities and isn’t afraid to use them,” &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;time.com&#x2F;6153902&#x2F;russia-major-cyber-attacks-invasion-ukraine&#x2F;&quot;&gt;writes Josephine Wolff&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, associate professor of cybersecurity policy at Tufts University. “Especially on Ukraine.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading up to the invasion, Ukraine experienced a series of cyberattacks on its critical infrastructures, including banks and government agencies. On February 23 2022, just a day before the launch of Russia’s military attack, websites of the Ukrainian parliament and multiple government agencies were put out of work. Similar cyber attacks had also been seen in early February and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.economist.com&#x2F;europe&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;23&#x2F;will-war-in-ukraine-lead-to-a-wider-cyber-conflict?utm_campaign=a.io&amp;amp;utm_medium=audio.podcast.np&amp;amp;utm_source=babbage&amp;amp;utm_content=discovery.content.anonymous.tr_shownotes_na-na_article&amp;amp;utm_term=sa.listeners&quot;&gt;were attributed to GRU&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Russia’s military-intelligence agency. And Ukrainian cities continue to suffer from &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.economist.com&#x2F;graphic-detail&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;26&#x2F;ukrainian-cities-are-suffering-internet-blackouts?utm_campaign=a.io&amp;amp;utm_medium=audio.podcast.np&amp;amp;utm_source=babbage&amp;amp;utm_content=discovery.content.anonymous.tr_shownotes_na-na_article&amp;amp;utm_term=sa.listeners&quot;&gt;internet blackouts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. On Sunday, Ukraine’s vice president even called for tech specialists and hackers to join the “cyber front.” While the predictions of a Russian “cyber onslaught” have not necessarily come true yet, both sides have engaged in cyber attacks on visible and invisible levels.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-rise-in-state-sponsored-cyber-attacks-globally&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#a-rise-in-state-sponsored-cyber-attacks-globally&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: a-rise-in-state-sponsored-cyber-attacks-globally&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;A Rise in State-Sponsored Cyber Attacks Globally&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital or cyber warfare does not just apply to Russia and Ukraine. Broadly, cybersecurity experts have been raising concerns in recent years amid a sharp rise in ransomware and other types of digital attacks globally.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam Meyers, Senior Vice President of Intelligence at the cybersecurity firm CrowdStrike &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.marketplace.org&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;24&#x2F;cybersecurity-to-take-center-stage-as-conflict-continues-in-ukraine&#x2F;&quot;&gt;said&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: “Just in the last year, I think we’ve seen over 2,700 big-game hunting attacks [cyberattacks that target high-value data]. So they’re far and away that most prevalent actor. Nation-state actors are continuously operating as well, but they tend to operate a little bit more under the radar. They don’t conduct as many widespread and widely known attacks. They try to, obviously, steal information without it being identified that they’ve stolen it.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, these are just the most current examples – Russia is hardly the only country engaging in cyber warfare at a larger scale. In fact, it is becoming increasingly difficult for governments, corporations and organizations to protect themselves against cyber attacks, especially against &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.economist.com&#x2F;business&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;19&#x2F;companies-have-a-lot-to-fear-from-russias-digital-warmongering?utm_campaign=a.io&amp;amp;utm_medium=audio.podcast.np&amp;amp;utm_source=babbage&amp;amp;utm_content=discovery.content.anonymous.tr_shownotes_na-na_article&amp;amp;utm_term=sa.listeners&quot;&gt;state-sponsored attacks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. And in the digital space, the best and most dangerous hacks are those that go unnoticed until it’s too late.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-governments-are-sectioning-off-the-internet-through-digital-borders&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#some-governments-are-sectioning-off-the-internet-through-digital-borders&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: some-governments-are-sectioning-off-the-internet-through-digital-borders&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Some Governments are Sectioning Off the Internet Through Digital Borders&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A set of countries like Russia, China, Saudi Arabia, and Iran have certain &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.codastory.com&#x2F;authoritarian-tech&#x2F;global-rise-internet-sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;aspirations for the internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Domestically, these countries want control and think governments should get to decide what information flows across their borders. Globally, they want governments, not companies and NGOs, to be in charge of the internet. While some may say that government-owned internet infrastructures would be the only way to protect a country’s sovereignty, it goes without saying that what once was a neutral space for humanity to connect and exchange information is turning into a political schema.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken together, these goals are an attempt to align cyberspace with national borders, so they are sometimes dubbed the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.codastory.com&#x2F;authoritarian-tech&#x2F;global-rise-internet-sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;“cyber sovereignty” doctrine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The term comes from China, whose internet censorship system, called the Great Firewall, is the vanguard of the global cyber-sovereignty push. China’s cyberspace agency released a much-ridiculed musical ode to cybersecurity under Lu Wei’s leadership, which included the line: “A cyberpower: Where the Internet is, so is the glorious dream.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vision of effective cyber-sovereignty is expanding to new horizons. A November &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.codastory.com&#x2F;authoritarian-tech&#x2F;global-rise-internet-sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;report&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from Freedom House examined 65 countries and found since the previous year that internet freedom declined in 26 of them. Chinese-style “digital authoritarianism,” meanwhile, is growing in influence as China exports both its surveillance known-how and technology.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem here is that digital sovereignty is a major concept that not only addresses the issues of communication and connection but also the impact on societies and culture at large. With cyber sovereignty turning into a non-territorial challenge to sovereignty itself irrespective of the virtual realm of the internet, is there a way out for humanity?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-free-and-sovereign-cyber-space-is-needed&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#a-free-and-sovereign-cyber-space-is-needed&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: a-free-and-sovereign-cyber-space-is-needed&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;A Free and Sovereign Cyber Space is Needed&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is evident that the current internet is facing some big challenges that have major implications for humanity. Data privacy and self-sovereignty is almost impossible today, raising serious questions towards those that control the Internet. But it also seems that these companies fell into the trap of their own business models and algorithms.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When taking a step back, the world seems just a few years away from the Matrix, as depicted by the Wachowskis.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet is playing an incredibly important role for the most powerful intelligence companies. As depicted by Meyers, we wouldn’t even notice that our information is being stolen all the time to benefit the greed of powerful geo-political actors. The internet is not a public good anymore, and unless humanity reacts fast, it may be that the world will lose all forms of freedom or sovereignty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.eff.org&#x2F;cyberspace-independence&quot;&gt;“A declaration of the Independence of Cyberspace”&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by John Perry Barlow once attempted to shed light on the applicability of government and institutions on the rapidly growing internet, already in 1996 trying to protect its neutrality. According to research, the world is experiencing innovation at an increasingly rapid pace. With the rise of blockchains and web3 technology, could the dream of John Perry Barlow turn into reality?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-the-solution&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#so-what-is-the-solution&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: so-what-is-the-solution&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;So, What is the Solution?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world aching for more decentralization and less dependence on governments and corporations, new decentralized and peer-to-peer models are already proving to be more resilient and secure. New Internet infrastructure companies such as ThreeFold have successfully built peer-to-peer internet infrastructures that are more resilient than the current centralized model. On such systems, people and enterprises can store their data and run their applications on a distributed network of computers in such a way that their data cannot be corrupted. ThreeFold even created a so-called “quantum safe” storage that guarantees that even the most powerful computers in the world wouldn’t be able to reconstruct user data.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The escalation of this cyber conflict can lead to unforeseen consequences and casualties. That is why it is especially important that our industry works together to protect customers, partners, employees and citizens. ThreeFold is on a mission to realize the promise of a fully-comprehensive, open-source and peer-to-peer internet infrastructure. ThreeFold is a platform for the creators of tomorrow to build that blueprint of responsibility and ensure that the outcome of future systems is neutrality.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;Br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join ThreeFold in building the new internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>The ThreeFold Grid is by the People, For the People</title>
		<published>2021-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/tf-grid-peoples-internet/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/tf-grid-peoples-internet/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What do you think of when you hear the word Internet? For many, it’s the websites and applications we consume online as end users. But the Internet is much more than this. And ultimately, every action we take online goes through a complex set of automated processes and protocols to store, run, and transmit data (e.g. photos, videos, messages, other files) across the global Internet infrastructure.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, this infrastructure consists of massive, power-hungry data centers, and is largely privatized and owned by tech giants such as Facebook, Google and Amazon – who also happen to own the biggest online “free” platforms. But there’s a catch. By owning both the infrastructure and the digital experiences we consume for free, we were actually turned into products of their business models. Our data is being collected and isn’t owned by us anymore. While data has become the most valuable commodity on earth, don’t you think it’s wrong that we don’t own the value of our data today? 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Today, every individual is worth between US $1,000 and $20,000 online, per year. The Internet and Cloud Industry is worth trillions, yet all this value is centralized to a handful of companies. This has to change.”&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold’s open source technology powers the peer-to-peer Internet revolution that holds the premise to disrupt the global Internet in many ways.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-internet-by-the-people&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#an-internet-by-the-people&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: an-internet-by-the-people&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;An Internet By the People&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ThreeFold Grid is formed by people from all around the world that connect Internet capacity to a peer-to-peer Infrastructure owned by humanity. Together, we expand a data-sovereign and planet-positive Internet infrastructure that puts people back in control of their data, and their digital lives. ThreeFold’s infrastructure can store all of humanity’s data – from personal data to public datasets and security archives – and can run all emerging technologies such as blockchain, IoT, and Big Data – with more efficiency and security.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold flips the current data center model upside-down, and allows people around the globe to connect Internet capacity in the form of hardware, and earn income for it. This decentralized approach means that anyone can take part in the world’s largest and fastest growing economy – the Internet and Cloud. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
You can see now how this new Internet is by the people, but how about the latter? What does the ThreeFold Grid enable?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-internet-for-the-people&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#an-internet-for-the-people&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: an-internet-for-the-people&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;An Internet For the People&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now anyone, anywhere can connect to the ThreeFold Grid and use capacity with some key advantages:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;a-world-where-we-own-the-value-of-our-data&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#a-world-where-we-own-the-value-of-our-data&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: a-world-where-we-own-the-value-of-our-data&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;A World Where we Own the Value of Our Data&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, all of the data we create online sits inside of centralized data centers and we do not own it. ThreeFold turns terms &amp;amp; conditions on their head and gives us, the people, full control of our data rather than third parties. We can keep our data private, decide with whom to share it, and even decide on where it’s stored and located. And considering that our personal data is worth between US $1,000 and $20,000 per year, ThreeFold offers a direct way for us to own our digital life and the value attached to it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-exchange-value-without-intermediaries&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#we-exchange-value-without-intermediaries&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: we-exchange-value-without-intermediaries&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;We Exchange Value Without Intermediaries&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “People’s Internet” is peer-to-peer. This means connections between senders and recipients are completely end-to-end, eliminating the need for any form of intermediaries from the model. Can you imagine what the world would look like without intermediaries? Let’s take an example like Airbnb.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, if you are looking for a place to stay on vacation, you will probably end up using the services of Airbnb. But did you know that Airbnb charges both consumers and property owners for using their service? In a peer-to-peer world, this wouldn’t be necessary. You’d simply access a database of property owners (possibly through a peer-to-peer marketplace) and be able to complete the transaction yourselves. No hidden fees, just a direct exchange of value!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;applications-run-on-the-edge&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#applications-run-on-the-edge&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: applications-run-on-the-edge&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Applications Run on the Edge&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its essence, edge computing brings compute and storage closer to people (and the devices where it’s being gathered) rather than relying on a centralized data centers located on the other side of the planet. This is the essence of the ThreeFold Grid. So, data doesn’t suffer any latency issues (performance) and it’s far more efficient &#x2F; money-saving. Further, the distributed nature of the Grid allows for true privacy and security. Edge computing is not just a growing trend but, because of the growing number of connected devices and global Internet usage, it’s becoming a real necessity.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;but-what-about-the-planet&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#but-what-about-the-planet&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: but-what-about-the-planet&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;But what about the planet?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been following us, you must already know that the Internet is responsible for 10% or more of the world’s energy consumption. And with decades of experience in the Internet and Cloud industry, ThreeFold co-founders knew how to turn this around. We developed a lightweight operating system and infrastructure, removing unnecessary layers of complexity from the traditional and Web3 models (actually, blockchains are making it even more complex). The ThreeFold technology is always geared towards maximum efficiency while maintaing performance. And with these advancements, we can already save up-to 90% energy on storage workloads.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Additionally, the distributed nature of the Grid uses less bandwidth (see above re: edge computing). It’s been reported that Netflix alone takes up 15% of the Internet’s bandwidth. What if Netflix were to leverage the ThreeFold Grid? If stored closer to watchers, we could reduce network usage considerably.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Our commitment to the planet goes beyond the technology. Through a partnership with Take Action Global (TAG), we aim to take three times more CO2 out of the air compared to what we put in. Imagine regenerating the earth while using the Internet?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
At ThreeFold, we believe that it’s time for us to take back control. As the world turns more and more digital due to the pandemic and even just the natural progression of technology, it’s time that we not just realize the problems of today’s Internet, but that we do something about it.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This will happen! So join in, and spread the word! &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>It&#x27;s Time We Stand Up For Our Data</title>
		<published>2021-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/data-leaks/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/data-leaks/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Do a quick search for “data leak” on your search engine of choice, and you’ll likely see headlines like this:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal Details of Over 3.3M Volkswagen Customers Exposed in Data Leak&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Billions of emails and passwords appear in largest data leak ever&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Here’s How the IRS Could Have Prevented the Tax Data Leak&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Time to Change Your Password: Tips on Protecting Yourself from Online Scams
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Week after week, month after month, year after year, companies are being hacked, private consumer data is being compromised and released, and we somehow begin to think that this is the reality of our world, something we just have to deal with.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Internet security, cyber attacks, and data leaks are a global threat – and increasingly so as the world moves more digital, and smart people with malicious intent try to take advantage. But this is not normal, nor should it be. As consumers, we should be able to trust that our data is truly safe and secure. And today, we cannot. It’s time we stand up for what is ours.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That’s where ThreeFold comes in.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Many of today’s issues around cyber security and data privacy come from the lack of innovation in the IT industry over the last decades and the reliance on centralized hyper-scale data centers. ThreeFold has disrupted this model in a few ways:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
First, we started from the ground up. Some ThreeFold co-founders have been working in the cloud &amp;amp; storage space for over two decades, having built components of the cloud and Internet still used today. They knew that the only way to have a truly secure and data sovereign Internet was to rebuild the architecture and the technology components from scratch. So they did. A few years down the line, we’ve created a new operating system, a smart contract for IT, and a peer-to-peer network that can be scaled to anywhere by anyone.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Second, we removed people from the equation. IT has become so overly-complex that people are required in order to maintain it. Because of this, “backdoors” are needed to allow these gateholders to enter the systems and make necessary fixes. But this can lead to human error, and also allows people with malicious intent to make their way in as well. With Autonomous IT powering the ThreeFold Grid, the technology runs and heals itself, and drastically reduces the opportunity for humans to interfere.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
And lastly, your data is owned by you. Rather than relying on centralized data centers, the ThreeFold Grid is an Internet grid made up by independent ThreeFold “Farmers” from around the world who plug in capacity from their home or office. While they own the hardware, they do not own the data inside. User data is stored across multiple devices, and proprietary data storage algorithms ensure that the data cannot be retrieved by anyone besides the user – not the farmer, and not even us.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
As Einstein said, “We can’t solve our problems with the same level of thinking that created them.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We have a lot more information in &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;&quot;&gt;our wikis&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; about the technology, but what we want to emphasize here with you is that we don’t have to accept data leaks and hacking. There is an answer to the cybersecurity issues the world is facing. And that answer is ThreeFold.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How ThreeFold offers Data Sovereignty</title>
		<published>2021-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/threefold-data-sovereignty/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/threefold-data-sovereignty/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you’ve seen &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=uaaC57tcci0&quot;&gt;The Social Dilemma&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, you know all too well that today, people are being turned into products. Everything we do online – all of the data we upload and all of our digital activities – is tracked and oftentimes used against us. Targeted advertising is just the beginning.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Personal data is used by algorithms to make incredible important decisions, like whether someone should receive financial or health support or benefits. In China, people are now even receiving “scores” for their behaviors. It sounds like Black Mirror, but it’s real life.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
That’s the scary part. The good news is that things don’t have to be this way. ThreeFold is building the engine for an Internet where people can finally be data sovereign.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__why_intro?id=everyone-should-be-autonomous&quot;&gt;today’s Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, infrastructure is centralized. Companies provide services in exchange for your personal data, which is stored on servers in hyper-scale data centers owned by private companies.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In ThreeFold’s model, those servers are called &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__3node&quot;&gt;3Nodes&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and rather than sitting inside centralized data centers, they sit inside the homes or offices (or small data centers) owned by independent people and organizations called &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro?id=what-is-3node&quot;&gt;Farmers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. But the data inside is owned by the person or persons who put it there. They maintain access right as well. From a technical standpoint, data is dispersed across 3Nodes by &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;threefold__part5_ultra_efficient_storage?id=the-space-algorithm-of-storage&quot;&gt;an algorithm&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; that makes it such that nobody can access it. In addition, connections are peer-to-peer, meaning data goes directly between sender and recipient rather than passing through intermediaries as it does today – bringing further levels of security.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Thus, people can finally be data sovereign, knowing their data is safe, and truly theirs.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Not your average blockchain project</title>
		<published>2021-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/a-different-approach-to-blockchain/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/a-different-approach-to-blockchain/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we’re compared to blockchain projects. We love blockchains and have many partners there – CasperLabs, DigiByte, Polygon, and Dash, to name a few – but that’s just not what we are. Here’s a few ways we are different than the “typical” blockchain project.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-is-actually-much-more-than-a-blockchain&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#threefold-is-actually-much-more-than-a-blockchain&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: threefold-is-actually-much-more-than-a-blockchain&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;ThreeFold is actually much more than a blockchain&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is not actually even a blockchain project, rather it uses blockchain technology by combining it with other cutting-edge solutions. It’s way more that just a blockchain alternative to a public cloud. &lt;!--  --&gt;ThreeFold started everything from scratch – built a super-lightweight and shell-less operating system, and a fully autonomous (self-driving and self-healing) architecture to enable a true peer-to-peer infrastructure.  With zero intermediaries on the ThreeFold Grid,  that leads to high efficiency and minimum complexity.&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The blockchain database (BCDB) acts as a registry for the workloads on the Threefold Grid. Workloads can only be accessed and managed with the private key of the data owner. The BCDB can prove to any party that their workloads are executed exactly as intended and that their data is untouched.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In most distributed systems, data is stored multiple times to guarantee redundancy. This leads to a lot of unnecessary overhead and is also not the most secure mechanism. ThreeFold uses a dispersed storage algorithm to store the workloads on the ThreeFold Grid. &lt;!--  --&gt;The dispersed storage algorithm breaks data into shards and stores them on different nodes.&lt;!--  --&gt; This enables two things – first, performance efficiency (no need for consensus to run compute and storage) and second, energy efficiency (as there’s no more need for data duplication).
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As mentioned up top, we have many partners in the space and we are working with them to bring true decentralization to their blockchains.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-had-no-ico-nor-ieo-it-pre-farmed-its-tokens&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#threefold-had-no-ico-nor-ieo-it-pre-farmed-its-tokens&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: threefold-had-no-ico-nor-ieo-it-pre-farmed-its-tokens&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;ThreeFold had no ICO nor IEO. It pre-farmed its tokens&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold didn’t have an ICO or IEO. ICOs and IEOs are fundraising schemes for blockchains to sell tokens to investors either directly (ICO) or through regulated exchanges (IEO). Instead, ThreeFold pre-farmed (ThreeFold’s sustainable alternative to mining) its tokens prior to going to the market and listed them on several exchanges, public and decentralized.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This allowed ThreeFold to incentivize its early contributors, while also securing the ongoing development of the project until the launch of the Threefold Grid 2.0 in April 2020. Pre-mining is also an organic approach to the market, in line with ThreeFold’s values and vision of delivering products over using hype.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;product-over-hype&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#product-over-hype&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: product-over-hype&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Product over Hype&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, ICOs and IEOs were surrounded with hype. It is always very hard to judge the ability of a project to deliver its promises through a white paper.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Instead of fundraising with a white paper, the technological development remained the primary focus. For 4 years, ThreeFold developed the whole technology stack, starting with an operating-system built from scratch to the autonomous smart contract and virtual system administrator technology that enables a fully-autonomous peer-to-peer Cloud. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In 2020, ThreeFold held the public launch of the ThreeFold Token on Liquid Exchange. At that time, the ThreeFold Grid was already live in its 2nd version.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, you can go through the whole Threefold Universe and find ready-to-use products. You can participate in growing the world’s most advanced peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure, or use the peer-to-peer compute and storage capacity available on the P2P Cloud.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Actually, you are the product</title>
		<published>2021-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-01-27T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/actually-you-are-the-product/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/actually-you-are-the-product/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;actually-you-are-the-product&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#actually-you-are-the-product&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: actually-you-are-the-product&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Actually, you are the product&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now more than ever with this global pandemic happening since late 2019, our lives are being shaped by our interaction with the digital world - work meetings on Zoom followed by Skype or Messenger Video Call with your family before a quick run with your favourite running app and a google search for your next meal. Technologies and services offer us a lot and greatly improve our daily lives. But what’s the real cost of these tools we rely on so much? &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lot of companies, especially those offering free services, collect data about you. It might be data you knowingly and willingly share to enjoy the benefits of the service (name, age, email address,..) or data that you might not realize you are sharing, like your approximate location through your IP address or your social network identifier or apps accessing your contacts. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While some of this data, and its collection, may appear harmless to some, what happens behind the scenes is a real source of concern as the data collection is only the first step in a long and opaque process. Adtech companies combine this information and create an assumed picture of you that we may call a digital doppelganger - Your “digital secret identity”. Actually, you may have hundreds or thousands of different doppelgangers held by companies you’ve never heard of. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our data are so valuable that big tech giants spend so much time and effort building the platform that is useful for us and giving those platforms to us for free. Well, this data is collected for a single purpose: to better predict your behaviour and target you with ads. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Real example: &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a person who has never talked about their political views online, never shared anything related to politics, never donated any money and never mentioned anything even in their private emails. Now the algorithms models that had been developed can analyse his&#x2F;her Facebook likes or the music he&#x2F;she listen to and with high accuracy can predict their political affiliation, and then being the target of unnecessary ads. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;P.S: This is not only for political affiliation. It stands out for every products and service using these marketing tools. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Technology isn’t just hardware and software; it’s a fundamental component of every aspect of our lives and society. Inventions need to be created with social impact in mind. The invention should not be driven solely by profit, and the long-term effects should not be ignored and unknowable. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are not paying for it, you are not the customer. You are the product being sold. It’s a powerful phrase, a modern dialogue to get people rethinking their relationship to social media. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Digital Twin, regain your freedom where you will live your digital life securely and privately. Now, you will have one and unique digital identity to interact in human-to-human way with your peers, edit, manage and store your documents, publish your web and make automatic payments. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Digital Twin, only you own your data and no one else.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
