<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
	<title>ThreeFold - sacha_obeegadoo</title>
	<subtitle>Our global digital backbone</subtitle>
	<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/people/sacha-obeegadoo/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
  <link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io"/>
	<generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
	<updated>2022-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
	<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/people/sacha-obeegadoo/atom.xml</id>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Connecting the Dots: ThreeFold plans to scale globally</title>
		<published>2022-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/connecting-the-dots/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/connecting-the-dots/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold started as an idea about ten years ago and is now manifesting itself into the most comprehensive peer-to-peer Internet and cloud infrastructure in the world. The potential of our technology to revolutionize digitization globally is endless and limited only to our collective imagination. In this blog, we share our ‘glocal’ strategy on how we will build our ecosystem, and the exciting opportunities opening up around the world for those interested to join us!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with some background. Today’s Internet is global*. However, it is incredibly centralized and vulnerable. ThreeFold aims to decentralize its infrastructure,  empower people to be sovereign, and accelerate the world’s transition towards open-source systems to build a more inclusive and fair future for all. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A peer-to-peer Internet has an undeniable potential in driving a distributed global economy. This is for a number of reasons – including, but not limited to the fact that instead of relying on centralized cloud providers and tech giants to expand the infrastructure that holds humanity’s data and applications, the peer-to-peer Internet allows any global citizen to participate in the Internet economy by connecting a computer from their house or office to build the decentralized future they want to live in.  Also, while half of the world takes Internet access for granted, it remains  unavailable to the other half.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;*So then is the Internet really “global?”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;empowering-sovereignty-and-economic-freedom&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#empowering-sovereignty-and-economic-freedom&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: empowering-sovereignty-and-economic-freedom&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Empowering sovereignty and economic freedom&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Billions of people around the world still remain without access to the Internet or financial services today. Yet many of them have access to electricity and network, and some even already own a mobile phone that could help them access the Internet and financial services. But without fair and reliable connectivity, they remain in the dark. ThreeFold holds an answer here.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet is a human right but it is unequally distributed around the world. ThreeFold enables the realization of an open-source, peer-to-peer Internet that can scale to anywhere electricity and network exists. Everyone deserves access to the Internet, education and financial services to equally learn, partake and succeed, regardless of where they were born, their gender or their socioeconomic status.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-how-can-threefold-go-truly-global&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#so-how-can-threefold-go-truly-global&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: so-how-can-threefold-go-truly-global&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;So how can ThreeFold go truly global?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going global is complicated and even more these days with the evolving regulatory and socio-economical landscapes. Thus, it’s important for us to be on the ground. So we will work with our community and ecosystem on one hand, and with governments and regulators on the other hand, for all of us to meet in the middle. We will always aim to be the most transparent, trusted, inclusive and decentralized Internet solution wherever we go. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A first step in our strategy is to support the growth of local communities across regions to build local presence on the ground. The only way for a truly decentralized Internet to emerge is to involve people in the building process of it, both on a hardware and software level. We are in the midst of kicking off an extensive global expansion strategy, with grants and hiring plans to grow the ThreeFold Grid across markets and ultimately build strong local communities that can serve potential customers locally. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Together with these communities, we will develop and grow the ThreeFold Grid, establish our presence with local developers, grow our ecosystem, and collaborate closely with our network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout the last year we have made incredible connections across industries including Blockchain, Web 3.0, IoT, Real Estate and Supply Chains.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every region is unique and we cannot take the same approach wherever we go. This is where the idea of ‘glo-cality’ comes in – a global concept applied locally with regional context.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;global-concept-launch-of-educational-campaigns-around-the-importance-of-a-peer-to-peer-internet&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#global-concept-launch-of-educational-campaigns-around-the-importance-of-a-peer-to-peer-internet&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: global-concept-launch-of-educational-campaigns-around-the-importance-of-a-peer-to-peer-internet&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Global Concept: Launch of educational campaigns around the importance of a peer-to-peer Internet&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s mission is to realize the promise of an open-source, peer-to-peer Internet owned by humanity, and we take this commitment heartedly. The first objective of our global strategy is to allow anyone who wants to expand the peer-to-peer Internet to their neighborhood to be able to find compatible computers and how to get started. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a multi-region approach to scaling the ThreeFold Grid to arise, a decentralized 3Node marketplace will be launched in April 2022. This will allow communities to access a simple, decentralized and certified platform to buy and sell compatible computer hardware locally. As the ThreeFold Grid expands, we will look to go local, as shared below:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;applied-locally-grow-localized-ecosystems-of-developers-and-enterprises-to-productize-the-infrastructure&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#applied-locally-grow-localized-ecosystems-of-developers-and-enterprises-to-productize-the-infrastructure&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: applied-locally-grow-localized-ecosystems-of-developers-and-enterprises-to-productize-the-infrastructure&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Applied locally: Grow localized ecosystems of developers and enterprises  to productize the infrastructure&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most countries are looking for new Internet infrastructure alternatives to protect their sovereignty. ThreeFold’s peer-to-peer Internet supports any current and emerging technological trend in a way that is fully compliant with any local digital laws and regulations. For developers and  enterprises, this includes a peer-to-peer Infrastructure as a service which offers a distributed, quantum-safe storage and a decentralized edge computing platform to host any current or future technology. For institutions, we will offer a suite of advanced infrastructure set-ups for a sovereign and unbreakable Internet infrastructure. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Decentralized financial and legal systems are being created along with industry experts from around the world to deliver on cross-border financial freedom, education and Internet access. Along with a strong ecosystem, we are planning to offer a full suite of advanced technological, financial and educational solutions to countries, especially in the global south to bring access to education, Internet and financial inclusion to more than a billion people by 2030.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At ThreeFold, we’re committed to building and expanding the open Internet that is owned by humanity. We are always looking at expanding our ecosystem with the world’s best thinkers and talent ready to be at service of a mission that unites us all. If you think this could be you, we’re waiting for you! &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you read our &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;blog&#x2F;realizing_the_promise&#x2F;&quot;&gt;manifesto&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; yet? Join the peer-to-peer &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;movement&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; today!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apply for an open position &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;careers&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and bring your proposals to the community-led &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;about-the-join-the-fold-category&#x2F;2570&quot;&gt;forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Co-Realizing the Promise</title>
		<published>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/realizing-the-promise/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/realizing-the-promise/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;What was once a massive global movement sparked by the idealism of free culture and the net, is now hosting a wave of unintended consequences that may destroy sovereignty and freedom as we know it. The digital revolution and the “democratization” of the Internet promised to lead us to a prosperous and equitable world, one that brought us closer together, eliminating both physical and virtual boundaries.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“We are creating a world that all may enter without privilege or prejudice accorded by race, economic power, military force, or station of birth… a world where anyone, anywhere may express his or her beliefs, no matter how singular, without fear of being coerced into silence or conformity… Your legal concepts of property, expression, identity, movement, and context do not apply to us. They are all based on matter, and there is no matter here.” –  Declaration of independence of Cyberspace – John Perry Barlow – Davos, 1996.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, this is not the world we live in today. Borders are hardening in our virtual world with the Great Firewall of China and the widespread emergence of Internet “clusters”. Many countries have attempted to turn off Internet services or to prevent free speech. Networks and algorithms turn us into data generators, influencing our daily habits and interests. It’s turning into a big AI-driven machine that commoditizes our lives, leaves the underserved behind and fails to provide sovereignty where we gather.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A centralized Internet which is controlled by a handful of companies is a serious existential threat. The technology that connects us is now used to distract, manipulate, polarize, divide and control the way we think, act and live our lives. If emerging technologies such as IoT, Blockchain and the Metaverse are not hosted on a self-sovereign, peer-to-peer infrastructure owned by all of us, we may be running head down into the matrix.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With billions of people and IoT devices expected to join this broken digital world this decade, we have no choice but to heal our broken information ecosystem if we want to address the challenges we face collectively. So as we move towards a world where tech and science are merging together, how do we ensure a neutral, inclusive and regenerative digital future – one that truly serves humanity and eliminates the barriers that divide us?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The peer-to-peer Internet incentivizes all citizens of our world to connect computers from their homes or offices to participate in a distributed data economy owned by the people. By allowing humans and machines to interweave without intermediaries, a decentralized and self-sovereign Internet can emerge.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite simply – there is no good reason that our data is being stored and controlled by others in the information age. Why are we paying centralized companies to handle our information on our  behalf, when it makes us vulnerable to be turned into products, and would take us the same time to do it ourselves?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer isn’t an alternative to the Internet, it’s an alternative to centralized cloud giants. The Internet doesn’t need replacing; it is one of the most beautiful inventions of our civilization, if not the greatest. Which is not to say that cloud providers are completely obsolete. They serve functions that decentralized systems cannot (e.g. big data); but peer-to-peer systems are just infinitely more resilient, secure, private and scalable.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In times of exponential evolution and innovation, we have our fears around the Internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t need to disconnect ourselves even further from our reality and it is our responsibility to ensure a safe and fair future for the generations to come. A centralized Internet which is controlled by a handful of companies is a serious existential threat. If emerging technologies such as IoT, Blockchain and the Metaverse are not hosted on a self-sovereign, peer-to-peer infrastructure owned by all of us, we may be running head down into the matrix. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The potential of technology to change the world remains endless and limited to our own imagination. We decide to switch from fear to love, and to move forward as one humanity. It is our responsibility as global citizens to pursue greater collective consciousness.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;t.me&#x2F;threefold&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; movement, a community of like-minded people that build the world of tomorrow!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;farm&quot;&gt;host the Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; at your home or office.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;gettft.com&#x2F;gettft&#x2F;&quot;&gt;TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, the currency of the peer-to-peer Internet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>What Bitcoin did to money, ThreeFold is doing to the Internet</title>
		<published>2022-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/bitcoin-threefold/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/bitcoin-threefold/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The world’s most famous cryptocurrency Bitcoin, established in 2008 by a person or group of people under the pseudonym of Satoshi Nakamoto, is changing the world. With 106 million people owning Bitcoin after only twelve years, the growth momentum is undeniable. The popularity of Bitcoin is transforming monetary systems at large, and establishing trust through irrefutable records.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike traditional financial technologies, Bitcoin provides total control over one’s funds without the intervention of a central authority, such as a bank or government. Bitcoin is decentralized and spread across many computers worldwide. It’s not a company, it’s a protocol. No single person or entity can control, manipulate or influence the network’s operations. There has never been a hack at the network level since Bitcoin launched in 2009.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin sparked a revolution towards decentralized and peer-to-peer systems. The advantage of such systems is that they operate without central authority, can be audited by anyone, and push for collaboration as their designs are public, inviting everyone to take part.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New systems built from scratch, like DeFi (decentralized finance), don’t have the problem of legacy firms, but they face challenges in scaling towards mass adoption. Most of the so-called ‘Web3’ solutions provide the illusion of decentralization but are actually still quite centralized. Others still have to prove their scalability, security and accessibility to become real alternatives to the current tech giants. While that may change, it’s not a given considering the clear limitations they have to overcome.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet represents the second largest and fastest growing economy in the world. With plenty of technologies emerging such as Blockchain, Web3, IoT and the Metaverse to name just a few, the infrastructure that holds our digital world together is becoming more important than ever before. However, the Internet is struggling with many issues related to its incredibly centralized model, including a lack of resiliency and scalability, as well as the loss of its neutrality. And these issues keep intensifying.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon Web Services alone hosts more than a third of the Internet today. Adding in a few other tech giants, we essentially end up with only four or five companies controlling the majority of the Internet. While the US government has been debating potential regulations and even breakups of big tech corporations, other governments like China or Russia are already regulating certain aspects of the web. However, most regulations have failed to achieve the desired outcomes and are unable to keep up with the pace of innovations.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a saying that goes, “If it is free, you are the product.” Social media platforms like Facebook and Instagram are known for being completely free of charge. Their business models and profits are based on collecting, analyzing and selling their users’ data. &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.mcleanhospital.org&#x2F;essential&#x2F;it-or-not-social-medias-affecting-your-mental-health&quot;&gt;Studies&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; now show that high social media use correlates with self-reported declines in mental and physical health. The same platforms are being manipulated by private companies that spread political disinformation and polarity. According to internal Facebook &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.theverge.com&#x2F;2020&#x2F;5&#x2F;26&#x2F;21270659&#x2F;facebook-division-news-feed-algorithms&quot;&gt;reports&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, 64% of the people that joined extremist groups did so because algorithms steered them there. In an increasingly interconnected world where people are surrounded by smart devices that collect their data 24&#x2F;7, data ownership and control has never been more important than anything else.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the launch of Bitcoin, many cryptocurrencies have rallied the movement of decentralization, but only a handful hold technology that can bring true impact. What if there was one project out there that could apply the peer-to-peer and open-source fundamentals to the Internet? ThreeFold spent the last six years developing a new Internet infrastructure from the ground up consisting of a new decentralized operating system, a quantum safe storage system, a planetary mesh network and a distributed edge cloud solution.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold builds on 20+ years of technological innovations in the cloud automation, Internet storage and cybersecurity markets brought by its co-founders such as Kristof de Spiegeleer – a serial entrepreneur whose technologies have been acquired by Oracle, Verizon, Data Symantec and others. Together, the ThreeFold co-founders decided to start from scratch as they realized it was the only way to achieve a peer-to-peer and open-source digital backbone that secure, private and self-sovereign.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to de Spiegeleer, “ThreeFold holds more technology than all the Web3 space combined.” ThreeFold’s decentralized operating system can run on any computer, including servers, desktops and laptops, allowing anyone to connect hardware from their home or office to the peer-to-peer Internet.“&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what differentiates ThreeFold the most from the crowd is that it’s a project anchored in it’s values and vision. The project always remained far from fake hype, market making or FOMO games like the large majority of crypto projects. With a low market cap today, and its ability to transform the Internet at large, the time to buy &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&#x2F;tft&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Tokens (TFT)&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is now. “We’re on the verge of signing our first countries and also have use cases across Real Estate, Education, Supply Chain, Metaverse and Blockchain coming up this year,” said de Spiegeleer, “So, we believe we are looking at tens of millions of users on ThreeFold in the upcoming years.“&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stake your claim in the decentralized Internet by &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_intro&quot;&gt;hosting the Internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tokens&#x2F;threefold__how_to_buy&quot;&gt;getting TFT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Can a &#x27;Democratized&#x27; Internet exist in times of a Cyber War?</title>
		<published>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/cyberwar/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/cyberwar/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;On February 24 2022, Russia launched a large-scale military invasion and attack on Ukraine. In the days since the invasion began, the war has been fought not only on the ground and in the air, but also in the digital realm.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyber warfare is nothing new, especially in Russia and Eastern Europe. “In the relatively short and rapidly evolving history of cyber conflict, perhaps nothing has been established with greater certainty and more widely accepted than the idea that Russia has significant cyber capabilities and isn’t afraid to use them,” &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;time.com&#x2F;6153902&#x2F;russia-major-cyber-attacks-invasion-ukraine&#x2F;&quot;&gt;writes Josephine Wolff&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, associate professor of cybersecurity policy at Tufts University. “Especially on Ukraine.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading up to the invasion, Ukraine experienced a series of cyberattacks on its critical infrastructures, including banks and government agencies. On February 23 2022, just a day before the launch of Russia’s military attack, websites of the Ukrainian parliament and multiple government agencies were put out of work. Similar cyber attacks had also been seen in early February and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.economist.com&#x2F;europe&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;23&#x2F;will-war-in-ukraine-lead-to-a-wider-cyber-conflict?utm_campaign=a.io&amp;amp;utm_medium=audio.podcast.np&amp;amp;utm_source=babbage&amp;amp;utm_content=discovery.content.anonymous.tr_shownotes_na-na_article&amp;amp;utm_term=sa.listeners&quot;&gt;were attributed to GRU&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, Russia’s military-intelligence agency. And Ukrainian cities continue to suffer from &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.economist.com&#x2F;graphic-detail&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;26&#x2F;ukrainian-cities-are-suffering-internet-blackouts?utm_campaign=a.io&amp;amp;utm_medium=audio.podcast.np&amp;amp;utm_source=babbage&amp;amp;utm_content=discovery.content.anonymous.tr_shownotes_na-na_article&amp;amp;utm_term=sa.listeners&quot;&gt;internet blackouts&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. On Sunday, Ukraine’s vice president even called for tech specialists and hackers to join the “cyber front.” While the predictions of a Russian “cyber onslaught” have not necessarily come true yet, both sides have engaged in cyber attacks on visible and invisible levels.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-rise-in-state-sponsored-cyber-attacks-globally&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#a-rise-in-state-sponsored-cyber-attacks-globally&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: a-rise-in-state-sponsored-cyber-attacks-globally&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;A Rise in State-Sponsored Cyber Attacks Globally&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Digital or cyber warfare does not just apply to Russia and Ukraine. Broadly, cybersecurity experts have been raising concerns in recent years amid a sharp rise in ransomware and other types of digital attacks globally.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adam Meyers, Senior Vice President of Intelligence at the cybersecurity firm CrowdStrike &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.marketplace.org&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;24&#x2F;cybersecurity-to-take-center-stage-as-conflict-continues-in-ukraine&#x2F;&quot;&gt;said&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;: “Just in the last year, I think we’ve seen over 2,700 big-game hunting attacks [cyberattacks that target high-value data]. So they’re far and away that most prevalent actor. Nation-state actors are continuously operating as well, but they tend to operate a little bit more under the radar. They don’t conduct as many widespread and widely known attacks. They try to, obviously, steal information without it being identified that they’ve stolen it.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, these are just the most current examples – Russia is hardly the only country engaging in cyber warfare at a larger scale. In fact, it is becoming increasingly difficult for governments, corporations and organizations to protect themselves against cyber attacks, especially against &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.economist.com&#x2F;business&#x2F;2022&#x2F;02&#x2F;19&#x2F;companies-have-a-lot-to-fear-from-russias-digital-warmongering?utm_campaign=a.io&amp;amp;utm_medium=audio.podcast.np&amp;amp;utm_source=babbage&amp;amp;utm_content=discovery.content.anonymous.tr_shownotes_na-na_article&amp;amp;utm_term=sa.listeners&quot;&gt;state-sponsored attacks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. And in the digital space, the best and most dangerous hacks are those that go unnoticed until it’s too late.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;some-governments-are-sectioning-off-the-internet-through-digital-borders&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#some-governments-are-sectioning-off-the-internet-through-digital-borders&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: some-governments-are-sectioning-off-the-internet-through-digital-borders&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Some Governments are Sectioning Off the Internet Through Digital Borders&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A set of countries like Russia, China, Saudi Arabia, and Iran have certain &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.codastory.com&#x2F;authoritarian-tech&#x2F;global-rise-internet-sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;aspirations for the internet&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Domestically, these countries want control and think governments should get to decide what information flows across their borders. Globally, they want governments, not companies and NGOs, to be in charge of the internet. While some may say that government-owned internet infrastructures would be the only way to protect a country’s sovereignty, it goes without saying that what once was a neutral space for humanity to connect and exchange information is turning into a political schema.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taken together, these goals are an attempt to align cyberspace with national borders, so they are sometimes dubbed the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.codastory.com&#x2F;authoritarian-tech&#x2F;global-rise-internet-sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;“cyber sovereignty” doctrine&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. The term comes from China, whose internet censorship system, called the Great Firewall, is the vanguard of the global cyber-sovereignty push. China’s cyberspace agency released a much-ridiculed musical ode to cybersecurity under Lu Wei’s leadership, which included the line: “A cyberpower: Where the Internet is, so is the glorious dream.”&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The vision of effective cyber-sovereignty is expanding to new horizons. A November &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.codastory.com&#x2F;authoritarian-tech&#x2F;global-rise-internet-sovereignty&#x2F;&quot;&gt;report&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; from Freedom House examined 65 countries and found since the previous year that internet freedom declined in 26 of them. Chinese-style “digital authoritarianism,” meanwhile, is growing in influence as China exports both its surveillance known-how and technology.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem here is that digital sovereignty is a major concept that not only addresses the issues of communication and connection but also the impact on societies and culture at large. With cyber sovereignty turning into a non-territorial challenge to sovereignty itself irrespective of the virtual realm of the internet, is there a way out for humanity?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-free-and-sovereign-cyber-space-is-needed&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#a-free-and-sovereign-cyber-space-is-needed&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: a-free-and-sovereign-cyber-space-is-needed&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;A Free and Sovereign Cyber Space is Needed&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is evident that the current internet is facing some big challenges that have major implications for humanity. Data privacy and self-sovereignty is almost impossible today, raising serious questions towards those that control the Internet. But it also seems that these companies fell into the trap of their own business models and algorithms.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When taking a step back, the world seems just a few years away from the Matrix, as depicted by the Wachowskis.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Internet is playing an incredibly important role for the most powerful intelligence companies. As depicted by Meyers, we wouldn’t even notice that our information is being stolen all the time to benefit the greed of powerful geo-political actors. The internet is not a public good anymore, and unless humanity reacts fast, it may be that the world will lose all forms of freedom or sovereignty.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.eff.org&#x2F;cyberspace-independence&quot;&gt;“A declaration of the Independence of Cyberspace”&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; by John Perry Barlow once attempted to shed light on the applicability of government and institutions on the rapidly growing internet, already in 1996 trying to protect its neutrality. According to research, the world is experiencing innovation at an increasingly rapid pace. With the rise of blockchains and web3 technology, could the dream of John Perry Barlow turn into reality?&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-the-solution&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#so-what-is-the-solution&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: so-what-is-the-solution&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;So, What is the Solution?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a world aching for more decentralization and less dependence on governments and corporations, new decentralized and peer-to-peer models are already proving to be more resilient and secure. New Internet infrastructure companies such as ThreeFold have successfully built peer-to-peer internet infrastructures that are more resilient than the current centralized model. On such systems, people and enterprises can store their data and run their applications on a distributed network of computers in such a way that their data cannot be corrupted. ThreeFold even created a so-called “quantum safe” storage that guarantees that even the most powerful computers in the world wouldn’t be able to reconstruct user data.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The escalation of this cyber conflict can lead to unforeseen consequences and casualties. That is why it is especially important that our industry works together to protect customers, partners, employees and citizens. ThreeFold is on a mission to realize the promise of a fully-comprehensive, open-source and peer-to-peer internet infrastructure. ThreeFold is a platform for the creators of tomorrow to build that blueprint of responsibility and ensure that the outcome of future systems is neutrality.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;Br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join ThreeFold in building the new internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>What is ThreeFold Farming?</title>
		<published>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2022-03-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/what-is-farming/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/what-is-farming/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold farming refers to the act of connecting a 3Node to the ThreeFold Grid – providing Internet capacity to a globally distributed peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure. Farming is a decentralized and energy-efficient way for people to expand a new Internet infrastructure instead of corporations building hyper-scale data centers. It’s also a way to extend the Internet to underserved regions of our planet, which cannot afford data centers. Every ThreeFold Farmer around the world contributes to the growth of the foundation for a self-sovereign, private and secure digital world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;.&#x2F;3node_example.png&quot; alt=&quot;3Node&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can start farming by hosting a computer at their home or office and taking part in the decentralization of our global Internet and Cloud economy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-become-a-threefold-farmer&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#why-become-a-threefold-farmer&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: why-become-a-threefold-farmer&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Why become a ThreeFold Farmer?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today’s Internet model is highly centralized, owned and operated by the few. It has turned people into products, is too harmful for our planet, cannot scale to meet emerging demands and connect the billions who are being left behind. These alone are powerful reasons to participate in ThreeFold farming and participate in the growth of a new peer-to-peer Internet economy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, the Internet is the second largest and fastest growing industry in the world after the financial markets. With the Internet expected to triple in size by 2025 to meet the data requirements of emerging technologies such as blockchain, Web3 and IoT, we need more capacity and especially in underserved regions of the world.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;basics-of-threefold-farming&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#basics-of-threefold-farming&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: basics-of-threefold-farming&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Basics of ThreeFold Farming&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is a peer-to-peer network of computers (known as “3Nodes”), including servers, desktops and laptops, that creates an open-source, decentralized Internet. People who connect computers to the ThreeFold Grid (known as “farmers”) are rewarded with ThreeFold Tokens (TFT) on a monthly basis for meeting the required uptime necessary for users to access their workloads.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The process of connecting decentralized Internet capacity and thereby creating new ThreeFold Tokens is described as farming because it resembles the process of farming in agriculture. With agricultural farming, farmers cultivate the land and earn revenue from their harvests. With ThreeFold, farmers connect decentralized Internet capacity and earn ThreeFold Tokens every month for achieving a certain uptime.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above model represents the building block for a distributed, edge infrastructure that can scale to anywhere electricity and network exists, to meet emerging data demands while also providing the self-sovereignty, privacy and security features to achieve true net-neutrality.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-fair-economic-model&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#a-fair-economic-model&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: a-fair-economic-model&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;A Fair Economic Model&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold was created to realize the promise of an open-source, peer-to-peer Internet. As such, ThreeFold farming rewards all farmers equally according to the amount of Internet capacity they provide to the network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold Tokens are rewarded for the amount of Internet capacity added and kept connected to the network. &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__farming_reward&quot;&gt;Farming rewards&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are calculated according to the compute, storage and network capacity made available by the computers:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 TFT per Compute Unit (2 vCPU and 4 GB memory) per month&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;12.5 TFT per Storage Unit (1 TB of SSD and HDD) per month&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.38 TFT per Network Unit (1 GB of data transfer)&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;0.06 TFT per public IP address per hour &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above prices are based on the price of 1 TFT equalling $0.08. The farming rewards are pegged to the U.S Dollar and the price is locked from the time a farmer gets started to incentivize early contributors to the network. When the price of TFT rises, the farming rewards will decrease.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farming rewards are designed to be “reviewed” by &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;decentralization&#x2F;dao&#x2F;threefold__tfdao&quot;&gt;the ThreeFold DAO&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (a decentralized autonomous organization owned by the ThreeFold community) according to the growth of the ThreeFold Grid and the utilization of its decentralized cloud to ensure a fair distribution of the token economy while also ensuring that farmers will always be justly rewarded for their contribution.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-innovative-and-sustainable-solution&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#an-innovative-and-sustainable-solution&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: an-innovative-and-sustainable-solution&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;An innovative and sustainable solution&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin mining and other blockchains became famous for requiring enormous amounts of computers and power to solve complex mathematical equations to win the chance of earning the famous cryptocurrency. Since then, many other projects have been born and carried on the mining concept.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s model is inclusive and planet-friendly. The decentralized operating system built and used by ThreeFold is extremely lightweight, allowing the peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure to be up-to 10x more energy efficient than the data center model and up-to 100x more energy efficient than Bitcoin mining.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The infrastructure was built in such a way that it removes the need for human intervention or maintenance to eliminate all unnecessary backdoors that open the possibility for ransomware and cyberattacks. Once booted, the decentralized operating system runs forever as the whole infrastructure was designed to be self-driving and self-healing. This 100% autonomous model allows for a completely decentralized system while also enhancing the security and privacy.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While blockchain remains an incredible store of value, it is neither an efficient nor a scalable solution to store data and run applications. Only a peer–to-peer model can scale the Internet infinitely and efficiently.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;considerations-before-getting-started&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#considerations-before-getting-started&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: considerations-before-getting-started&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Considerations before getting started&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are important factors to consider for ThreeFold farming profitability: &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;computer-hardware&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#computer-hardware&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: computer-hardware&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Computer Hardware&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farmers are encouraged to use the latest computers, including servers, desktops, and laptops that come with an AMD and Intel processor. The computer should have at least 1 Terabyte of SSD to optimize the performance of their farming activity. It is recommended to buy a ThreeFold 3Node server from certified partners around the globe that comes pre-configured and ready to run on the Grid. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Used or refurbished computers can be used but it is important to understand that older computers are less efficient and more power-hungry. Computers not older than 4 years are recommended. Please visit &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;c&#x2F;farming&#x2F;diy-farming&#x2F;43&quot;&gt;the DIY section of our forum&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for support and feedback on farming setups.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;power-costs&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#power-costs&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: power-costs&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Power Costs&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Electrical power is the  main operating expense. Electricity is charged per kilowatt-hour (kWh). The cost of farming can float from $0.10 to $0.35 per kWh. It is important for a farmer to verify the expected power usage of a computer before starting the operation to improve profitability.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that the price of kWh varies depending on the country. Find a country power cost average comparison &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.electricrate.com&#x2F;data-center&#x2F;electricity-prices-by-country&#x2F;&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;threefold-token-price&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#threefold-token-price&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: threefold-token-price&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;ThreeFold Token Price&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An incentive to farm ThreeFold Tokens is because of its future potential. What Bitcoin did to money, ThreeFold is doing to the Internet. While Bitcoin and Etheruem have already reached high market caps, ThreeFold is just getting started.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farmers are rewarded a given amount of TFT monthly based on the amount of Internet capacity they provide to the network.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the price of TFT is $0.1, the profitability of the farm will be average. If the price of TFT is $0.3  your farming operation may operate with healthy rewards. If the price of TFT is $1 your farming operation will be highly rewarding.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Farming rewards are also locked until 30% utilization for a period of 2 years to incentivize early participants. The earlier you start your farming operation, the greater the rewards along with the growth in the value of TFT.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right mix of the above elements make farming an attractive venture. If the variables are favorable, farmers can scale up operations and earn more rewards.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#conclusion&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: conclusion&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Conclusion&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyone can start farming by hosting a computer at their home or office and take part in the decentralization of our global Internet and Cloud economy. Considering ThreeFold’s market cap alongside the growing demand for a decentralized Internet, there’s no better time than now to get started farming!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;shop.threefold.tech&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Buy&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; or &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold#&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;farming&#x2F;threefold__diy_guide&quot;&gt;build&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; a 3Node and become a ThreeFold Farmer!&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>How ThreeFold Will Give Internet to 43% of the World’s Population</title>
		<published>2021-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-06-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/threefold-access/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/threefold-access/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The United Nations publicly ruled Internet access to be a human right in 2016. Proper access to the Internet helps to protect people’s freedom of speech and thought, as well as other fundamentals such as access to knowledge and information.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Nonetheless, as of 2019, about 43% of humanity remains unconnected to the Internet, creating huge inequalities in access to information and knowledge. It is essential to take the necessary steps to strengthen the relationship between governments and people while still upholding all human rights.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold created an infrastructure that is easily affordable and jointly operated by network peers to make the modern Internet open and fair to everyone. Anybody with a network connection and electricity can add capacity to the ThreeFold Grid. We’re looking for farmers around the globe and we’re also partnering with farming cooperatives to develop localized strategies and meet the specific needs of their region. Plus, the Foundation will incentivize and sponsor the extension and scope to areas that require Internet capacity the most, to ensure a fair and equitable delivery of the Internet to all.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Want to join the biggest internet revolution? &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;farming.threefold.io&quot;&gt;Be part&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; of it, today.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A Smart Contract for all IT workloads</title>
		<published>2021-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/smart-contract-blog/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/smart-contract-blog/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold was inspired by the blockchain burst when it was created in 2016. After doing a comprehensive scan of the technological space we realized that Blockchain holds the best technology to store (1) Smart Contracts and (2) Transactions in an immutable way. We created our own blockchain database: Rivine to host the Smart Contract layer before switching to the Parity Substrate of Polkadot and our Transactional blockchain to the Stellar Network.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
While we use blockchain technology, ThreeFold is much more than just “a blockchain project” as we apply many more revolutionary technologies. We decided to use Parity Substrate as we don’t see the need to create something if there’s already great technologies out there that we can already use. Today we’re proud of our Smart Contract for IT layer and approach the ThreeFold Grid v3.0 release this year which will expose its full potential to interact with the primitives of the grid.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-what-is-this-smart-contract-for-it-about&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#so-what-is-this-smart-contract-for-it-about&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: so-what-is-this-smart-contract-for-it-about&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;So what is this Smart Contract for IT about?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Smart Contract for IT allows you, your company or your community to execute the storage and running of your files and applications securely with consensus and automatic billing. You could compare it as a fingerprint check and your data would be accessible only if presenting your private key (fingerprint). Let’s maybe go through the process for a better idea of how this works.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The smart contracts are like recipes for chefs to cook exactly what you want. In that sense they need to be very accurate and as descriptive as possible to deliver what you need. In the case of ThreeFold, the smart contracts would define different sets of Internet resources you would need to store files, run applications, or communicate across the network.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Whenever you want to reserve more resources to store your latest album or run your applications, you will define the resources you need to your 3Bot or Digital Twin (your personal virtual system administrators) which will then look at different smart contracts that are available and choose the most appropriate package. For e.g. Reserve 3 PB of Storage in Switzerland across 7 nodes. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Following that, your 3Bot or Digital Twin will create and register the smart contract in the blockchain database in a few seconds, providing you with all your specific needs. It will also store and secure some instructions to the BCDB for the nodes to meet smart contract completion. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold had to make sure that user data would remain ultra-secure. Inspired by storage and communication algorithms used in space, we integrated it between the Smart Contract layer and Zero OS. The algorithm splits data into unrecognizable ‘slices’ that are distributed via network connections to different nodes locally or across the world, and that can be reconstructed only with your fingerprint. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;more-than-the-average-smart-contract&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#more-than-the-average-smart-contract&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: more-than-the-average-smart-contract&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;More than the average Smart Contract&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Via your Smart Contract for IT, you can also define a consensus mechanism and create multi-signatures for smart contract execution or completion to deliver appropriate digital services in for example work related activities. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The beauty of the Smart Contract for IT is that it can work with thousands of connected nodes for the proper execution of any digital requirements on the infrastructure, verify if consensus was reached or not, download the right files to execute the smart contract and verify them, make sure that no hacker or outsider can ever gain access or influence its execution and more. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
If you want to learn more about ThreeFold’s Smart Contract for IT, read more &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;internet4__smartcontract_it&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>A Scalable and Secure Operating System</title>
		<published>2021-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-05-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/zero-os-blog/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/zero-os-blog/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Just like a brain is an interconnected network of neurons, the Internet (or internet) is a global interconnected network of computers and devices that communicate with each other via the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Internet_protocol_suite&quot;&gt;Internet protocol suite&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; (TCP&#x2F;IP). The communications infrastructure of the Internet consists of hardware components and a system of software layers that control various aspects of the architecture.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
To create a new Internet from scratch, ThreeFold had to start at the operating system (OS) level. An operating system is a software that manages computer hardware, software resources, and provides common services for computer programs. And this is how Zero OS was born &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-makes-zero-os-special&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#what-makes-zero-os-special&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: what-makes-zero-os-special&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;What makes Zero OS special?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Zero OS is a stateless and lightweight operating system. Given it has no shell, remote or server interface, it is much safer than the big majority of the OSs on the market. When storing your data on Zero OS, it is fingerprinted and made available only when requested by you or those you provide access to.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The state of an application represents its state of being in a given moment in time. Think of a stateless transaction as vending machines, a single request and a response. In ThreeFold’s Internet infrastructure, this can be represented as data being accessible only when requested. 
The only way to access data on Zero OS is via the private key (or fingerprint) of a user. In that sense, the data is not accessible unless the data owner requests access to it. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-zero-os-apply-to-developers&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#how-does-zero-os-apply-to-developers&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: how-does-zero-os-apply-to-developers&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;How does Zero OS apply to developers?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to its lightweight architecture, Zero OS is a perfect fit to run microservice architectures and emerging IT workloads such as IoT, Blockchains, Big Data, and more. A key benefit of microservice architecture is the freedom it offers you to choose the best runtime for the task at hand. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Let’s take the example of decentralizing service-oriented developing teams. A common challenge there is that most of the time they don’t really understand the applications they are exposing. But no one knows the data infrastructure of the applications better than those who craft them. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold permits decentralized developer teams with the ability to share keys (access) to the developing environment on Zero OS and the gateways to the world wide web within the secure peer-to-peer overlay network. This is game changing. Also with all the automation frameworks provided, it creates the perfect environment to develop current and emerging technologies. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Put shortly, decentralized development and integration is now officially an organizational or cultural change, not a technical one anymore.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;zero-os-allows-anyone-to-provide-sovereign-capacity&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#zero-os-allows-anyone-to-provide-sovereign-capacity&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: zero-os-allows-anyone-to-provide-sovereign-capacity&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Zero OS allows anyone to provide sovereign capacity&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given stateless systems separate the OS configuration and user data, Zero OS simplifies the  maintenance and the deployment of digital workloads, while making it impossible to hack into user data on a hardware level. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
3Nodes provide all the storage, compute and network primitives for a new internet infrastructure. Given they are booted with Zero OS, anyone can now participate in the Internet economy without jeopardizing user data sovereignty and security.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Conclusively, Zero OS is ultra secure, perfect to develop current and future technologies, and enables anyone to take part in the planet positive and data sovereign Internet brought by ThreeFold.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Learn more about Zero OS and the grid primitives &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;threefold&#x2F;#&#x2F;internet4__tfgrid_primitives&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Not your average blockchain project</title>
		<published>2021-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-04-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/a-different-approach-to-blockchain/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/a-different-approach-to-blockchain/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we’re compared to blockchain projects. We love blockchains and have many partners there – CasperLabs, DigiByte, Polygon, and Dash, to name a few – but that’s just not what we are. Here’s a few ways we are different than the “typical” blockchain project.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-is-actually-much-more-than-a-blockchain&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#threefold-is-actually-much-more-than-a-blockchain&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: threefold-is-actually-much-more-than-a-blockchain&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;ThreeFold is actually much more than a blockchain&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold is not actually even a blockchain project, rather it uses blockchain technology by combining it with other cutting-edge solutions. It’s way more that just a blockchain alternative to a public cloud. &lt;!--  --&gt;ThreeFold started everything from scratch – built a super-lightweight and shell-less operating system, and a fully autonomous (self-driving and self-healing) architecture to enable a true peer-to-peer infrastructure.  With zero intermediaries on the ThreeFold Grid,  that leads to high efficiency and minimum complexity.&lt;!--  --&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The blockchain database (BCDB) acts as a registry for the workloads on the Threefold Grid. Workloads can only be accessed and managed with the private key of the data owner. The BCDB can prove to any party that their workloads are executed exactly as intended and that their data is untouched.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In most distributed systems, data is stored multiple times to guarantee redundancy. This leads to a lot of unnecessary overhead and is also not the most secure mechanism. ThreeFold uses a dispersed storage algorithm to store the workloads on the ThreeFold Grid. &lt;!--  --&gt;The dispersed storage algorithm breaks data into shards and stores them on different nodes.&lt;!--  --&gt; This enables two things – first, performance efficiency (no need for consensus to run compute and storage) and second, energy efficiency (as there’s no more need for data duplication).
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As mentioned up top, we have many partners in the space and we are working with them to bring true decentralization to their blockchains.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;threefold-had-no-ico-nor-ieo-it-pre-farmed-its-tokens&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#threefold-had-no-ico-nor-ieo-it-pre-farmed-its-tokens&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: threefold-had-no-ico-nor-ieo-it-pre-farmed-its-tokens&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;ThreeFold had no ICO nor IEO. It pre-farmed its tokens&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold didn’t have an ICO or IEO. ICOs and IEOs are fundraising schemes for blockchains to sell tokens to investors either directly (ICO) or through regulated exchanges (IEO). Instead, ThreeFold pre-farmed (ThreeFold’s sustainable alternative to mining) its tokens prior to going to the market and listed them on several exchanges, public and decentralized.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
This allowed ThreeFold to incentivize its early contributors, while also securing the ongoing development of the project until the launch of the Threefold Grid 2.0 in April 2020. Pre-mining is also an organic approach to the market, in line with ThreeFold’s values and vision of delivering products over using hype.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;product-over-hype&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#product-over-hype&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: product-over-hype&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Product over Hype&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some cases, ICOs and IEOs were surrounded with hype. It is always very hard to judge the ability of a project to deliver its promises through a white paper.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Instead of fundraising with a white paper, the technological development remained the primary focus. For 4 years, ThreeFold developed the whole technology stack, starting with an operating-system built from scratch to the autonomous smart contract and virtual system administrator technology that enables a fully-autonomous peer-to-peer Cloud. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In 2020, ThreeFold held the public launch of the ThreeFold Token on Liquid Exchange. At that time, the ThreeFold Grid was already live in its 2nd version.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, you can go through the whole Threefold Universe and find ready-to-use products. You can participate in growing the world’s most advanced peer-to-peer Internet infrastructure, or use the peer-to-peer compute and storage capacity available on the P2P Cloud.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Join the Conversation - The Cyber Pandemic is Here</title>
		<published>2021-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2021-01-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/newsroom/cyber-pandemic-convo/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/newsroom/cyber-pandemic-convo/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The cyber pandemic is here, but it’s not too late!
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Join in on an important discussion next Wednesday with ThreeFold founder, Kristof De Spiegeleer.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Registration: &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;swiss-social.com&#x2F;events&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Related links:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.youtube.com&#x2F;watch?v=oe3y-OdNSsw&quot;&gt;The Cyberpandemic has begun&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.interpol.int&#x2F;en&#x2F;News-and-Events&#x2F;News&#x2F;2020&#x2F;INTERPOL-report-shows-alarming-rate-of-cyberattacks-during-COVID-19&quot;&gt;INTERPOL report on COVID-19 cyberattacks&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.gcsp.ch&#x2F;global-insights&#x2F;why-cybersecurity-matters-more-ever-during-coronavirus-pandemic&quot;&gt;Why cybersecurity matters more than ever&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>What Is Peer-to-Peer and Why Is It so Important?</title>
		<published>2020-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-12-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/what-is-peer-to-peer/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/what-is-peer-to-peer/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#what-is-peer-to-peer&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: what-is-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;What is Peer-to-Peer?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peer-to-peer (P2P) is a term that originated from the distributed computer application architecture where tasks and workloads are shared between peers, popularized by &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Napster&quot;&gt;Napster&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, a revolutionary file storing system from the late 1990s.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The concept inspired new structures and philosophies in many areas of human interaction. P2P systems and groups are typically critical of authoritarian and centralized social structures and believe in equality, meritocracy, flat systems, participatory &amp;amp; circular economies, as the concept represents a concrete pathway to these outcomes or visions.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
P2P systems are network, not linear or ‘pyramidal’ hierarchies (though they may share some elements). They are ‘distributed’, though they may have elements of ‘centralization’ and ‘decentralization.’ And intelligence is not located at any center, but everywhere within the system.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-does-threefold-relate-to-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#how-does-threefold-relate-to-peer-to-peer&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: how-does-threefold-relate-to-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;How does ThreeFold relate to peer-to-peer?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold’s Peer-to-Peer (P2P) computing network is a distributed architecture that splits tasks and workloads between its peers, &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;what_is_farming&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Farmers&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Farmers are equal participants in the network and together they form a peer-to-peer network of nodes, the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Farmers make their resources, such as processing power, disk storage or network bandwidth, directly available to other network participants, without the need for central coordination by servers or stable hosts. Farmers are both suppliers and consumers of resources, in contrast to the traditional &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Client-server&quot;&gt;client-server&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; model in which the consumption and supply of resources is divided.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
In the near future, ThreeFold will create Digital Twin, which will go beyond the era of peers doing similar things while sharing resources. It will actually enable much more than that. Digital Twin will create a complete new digital world with diverse peers that can bring in unique resources and capabilities to a &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;en.wikipedia.org&#x2F;wiki&#x2F;Virtual_community&quot;&gt;virtual community&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; on the ThreeFold Grid. This will empower the network of peers to engage in greater tasks beyond those that can be accomplished by individual peers, and are beneficial to all the peers.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-did-threefold-choose-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#why-did-threefold-choose-peer-to-peer&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: why-did-threefold-choose-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Why did ThreeFold choose peer-to-peer? &lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything starts (or should start) from the why, and the ThreeFold story started a long time ago. Before the inception of ThreeFold, many of the co-founders of the project used to work with the largest IT &amp;amp; Cloud actors. Throughout their experience working in the Industry, they realized that the complexity of the technology and the centralization of knowledge &amp;amp; power led to an inefficient, unsustainable, not scalable and unequally distributed infrastructure. So they decided to redesign the whole Internet and cloud infrastructure bottom-up with the vision of shaping a global internet economy that can scale anywhere efficiently, cost efficiently and sustainably. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-does-the-world-needs-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#why-does-the-world-needs-peer-to-peer&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: why-does-the-world-needs-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Why does the world needs peer-to-peer? &lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By developing the technology, the conviction that peer-to-peer was the best solution for humanity and the planet strengthened itself. Why? Well, put simply, a peer-to-peer system removes all forms of intermediaries, unnecessary steps and complexity from the picture. Therefore, it simplifies the architecture in an incredible way. The benefits are many but here are the most popular benefits:
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Privacy&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: Our peer-to-peer environment means no middlemen or intermediaries, meaning data travels directly between peers and stored on the nodes of their choice rather than being sent through and stored by a third party.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Security&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: Data stored in data centers is susceptible to security breaches. In bypassing data centers and exchanging data directly between peers, we can achieve much greater security as it reduces code and back doors significantly. &lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scalability&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: In a many-to-many system, scale is essentially unlimited. There is simply no bottleneck. And hardware (nodes) can be added at ease compared to current data center model.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cost-efficiency &amp;amp; Sustainability&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;: End-to-end (direct) connection between peers means a more efficient path for data and less energy is needed. Less energy means less cost, and less harm to our planet.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-2021-the-world-is-going-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#in-2021-the-world-is-going-peer-to-peer&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: in-2021-the-world-is-going-peer-to-peer&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;In 2021 the world is going peer-to-peer! &lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We’re now in 4 years into the project, and it is clear that ThreeFold holds the most advanced technology and is probably the only tech company in the world that can achieve a peer-to-peer network &amp;amp; digital world as envisioned by the concept authors. The ThreeFold Grid is running and already at it’s 2.4 version and 2021 will bring various commercial opportunities for the public to partake in the peer-to-peer network, from hosting IT workloads to experiencing P2P end-user solutions. In other words, in 2021, the world will be able to go peer-to-peer.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Dash &amp; Dash NEXT partner with ThreeFold</title>
		<published>2020-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-07-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/newsroom/dash-threefold/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/newsroom/dash-threefold/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.dash.org&quot;&gt;Dash&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; &#x2F; &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;dashnext.org&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Dash NEXT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are excited to officially announce their collaboration, effective the end of June 2020.  Dash and ThreeFold are community-driven organizations focused on peer-to-peer solutions that strive for decentralization and the empowerment of humanity.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dash &#x2F; Dash NEXT and ThreeFold will work together on developer projects on the ThreeFold Grid. The Dash developer community, and anyone interested in contributing to the Dash Blockchain, is being invited to use a truly decentralized and  affordable cloud alternative - &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold P2P Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Developers can now deploy their Dash nodes and IT workloads on the ThreeFold Grid with an autonomous execution via &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;smart_contract&quot;&gt;Smart Contracts for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further, community members are being invited to explore possibilities in using the ThreeFold Grid’s capacity and peer-to-peer cloud for their own personal computing needs and projects. Anyone interested in being a node operator in the Dash Blockchain using the ThreeFold Grid would be highly encouraged to get started in a few steps following this &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;deploy-a-dash-node-in-5-steps-on-the-threefold-grid&#x2F;509&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Adnan Fatayerji, co-founder at ThreeFold, enthusiastically expressed his excitement working with the Dash developer community, “We are extremely excited about our collaboration with Dash [and Dash NEXT], a global name in decentralized transactions. We look forward to empowering their developer community with access to a global substrate of peer-to-peer storage and compute. Together we will drive financial and Internet inclusion to the edge of the network!”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dash community and any individual or organization interested in contributing to Dash are now empowered to deploy their Dash MasterNodes and any containerized IT workload using the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;http:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold P2P Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;, and benefit from  an autonomous execution via &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;smart_contract&quot;&gt;Smart Contracts for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Dash’s community is incentivized to get started with free compute and storage capacities offered by ThreeFold.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Felix Mago, Co-Founder at Dash NEXT shared his enthusiasm around that opportunity: “We are excited to have ThreeFold as a partner as they are enabling us to host Dash Masternodes in a decentralized manner.”
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;deploy-a-dash-node-in-5-steps-on-the-threefold-grid&#x2F;509&quot;&gt;You can follow this documentation to deploy full Dash nodes and MasterNodes on the ThreeFold grid  in 5 easy steps.&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-dash&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#about-dash&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: about-dash&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;About Dash:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dash is an open source peer-to-peer cryptocurrency with a strong focus on the payments industry. Dash offers a form of money that is portable, inexpensive, divisible and fast. It can be spent securely both online and in-person with only minimal transaction fees. Based on the Bitcoin project, Dash aims to be the most user-friendly and scalable payments system in the world.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In addition to Bitcoin’s feature set, Dash currently also offers instant transactions (&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.dash.org&#x2F;en&#x2F;stable&#x2F;introduction&#x2F;features.html#instantsend&quot;&gt;InstantSend&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;), private transactions (&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.dash.org&#x2F;en&#x2F;stable&#x2F;introduction&#x2F;features.html#privatesend&quot;&gt;PrivateSend&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;) and operates a self-governing and self-funding model that enables the Dash network to pay individuals and businesses for work that adds value to the network. This &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.dash.org&#x2F;en&#x2F;stable&#x2F;governance&#x2F;index.html#governance&quot;&gt;decentralized governance and budgeting system&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; makes it one of the first ever successful decentralized autonomous organizations (DAO).&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#about-threefold&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: about-threefold&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;About ThreeFold:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer Internet grid in the world.  They launched the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; V2.0 in  April 2020 – a  more performant, private &amp;amp; secure, affordable, and sustainable solution than centralized cloud and internet providers. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers (independent Internet capacity providers) around the globe, the ThreeFold Grid  is now open for developers to build on top of it,  and users can now benefit from all the advantages of the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Foundation aims to empower a more equal, autonomous (decentralized) and sustainable world, and does so  by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to the world, while incentivizing growth in developing regions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Harmony Integrates with ThreeFold’s Decentralized Grid</title>
		<published>2020-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-05-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/newsroom/harmony-threefold/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/newsroom/harmony-threefold/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;harmony-and-the-threefold-foundation-are-aligned-in-their-focus-on-empowering-an-equal-and-fair-world-doing-good-for-the-planet-and-humanity-is-at-the-core-of-both-organizations-dna-today-harmony-and-threefold-are-pleased-to-officially-announce-their-collaborative-partnership-harmony-and-threefold-will-work-together-on-developer-and-user-projects-on-the-threefold-grid-and-pangaea-harmony-s-developer-community-and-anyone-interested-in-contributing-to-their-blockchain-and-being-a-validator-within-the-harmony-staking-ecosystem-is-being-invited-to-use-a-more-decentralized-performant-and-affordable-peer-to-peer-cloud-solution-brought-by-threefold-developers-can-now-deploy-their-nodes-and-any-it-workloads-on-pangaea-and-the-threefold-grid-with-an-autonomous-execution-via-smart-contracts-for-it-anyone-interested-in-being-a-node-operator-as-a-validator-in-the-harmony-blockchain-using-the-threefold-grid-is-invited-to-get-started-in-a-few-steps-following-this-documentation-from-threefold-co-founder-adnan-fatayerji-we-re-super-excited-about-our-partnership-with-harmony-their-approach-to-decentralization-of-applications-and-transactions-perfectly-couples-with-our-approach-of-trying-to-bring-an-inclusive-internet-together-we-will-form-a-big-powerhouse-for-positive-change-in-this-world-threefold-and-harmony-look-forward-to-the-further-development-of-this-collaboration&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#harmony-and-the-threefold-foundation-are-aligned-in-their-focus-on-empowering-an-equal-and-fair-world-doing-good-for-the-planet-and-humanity-is-at-the-core-of-both-organizations-dna-today-harmony-and-threefold-are-pleased-to-officially-announce-their-collaborative-partnership-harmony-and-threefold-will-work-together-on-developer-and-user-projects-on-the-threefold-grid-and-pangaea-harmony-s-developer-community-and-anyone-interested-in-contributing-to-their-blockchain-and-being-a-validator-within-the-harmony-staking-ecosystem-is-being-invited-to-use-a-more-decentralized-performant-and-affordable-peer-to-peer-cloud-solution-brought-by-threefold-developers-can-now-deploy-their-nodes-and-any-it-workloads-on-pangaea-and-the-threefold-grid-with-an-autonomous-execution-via-smart-contracts-for-it-anyone-interested-in-being-a-node-operator-as-a-validator-in-the-harmony-blockchain-using-the-threefold-grid-is-invited-to-get-started-in-a-few-steps-following-this-documentation-from-threefold-co-founder-adnan-fatayerji-we-re-super-excited-about-our-partnership-with-harmony-their-approach-to-decentralization-of-applications-and-transactions-perfectly-couples-with-our-approach-of-trying-to-bring-an-inclusive-internet-together-we-will-form-a-big-powerhouse-for-positive-change-in-this-world-threefold-and-harmony-look-forward-to-the-further-development-of-this-collaboration&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: harmony-and-the-threefold-foundation-are-aligned-in-their-focus-on-empowering-an-equal-and-fair-world-doing-good-for-the-planet-and-humanity-is-at-the-core-of-both-organizations-dna-today-harmony-and-threefold-are-pleased-to-officially-announce-their-collaborative-partnership-harmony-and-threefold-will-work-together-on-developer-and-user-projects-on-the-threefold-grid-and-pangaea-harmony-s-developer-community-and-anyone-interested-in-contributing-to-their-blockchain-and-being-a-validator-within-the-harmony-staking-ecosystem-is-being-invited-to-use-a-more-decentralized-performant-and-affordable-peer-to-peer-cloud-solution-brought-by-threefold-developers-can-now-deploy-their-nodes-and-any-it-workloads-on-pangaea-and-the-threefold-grid-with-an-autonomous-execution-via-smart-contracts-for-it-anyone-interested-in-being-a-node-operator-as-a-validator-in-the-harmony-blockchain-using-the-threefold-grid-is-invited-to-get-started-in-a-few-steps-following-this-documentation-from-threefold-co-founder-adnan-fatayerji-we-re-super-excited-about-our-partnership-with-harmony-their-approach-to-decentralization-of-applications-and-transactions-perfectly-couples-with-our-approach-of-trying-to-bring-an-inclusive-internet-together-we-will-form-a-big-powerhouse-for-positive-change-in-this-world-threefold-and-harmony-look-forward-to-the-further-development-of-this-collaboration&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.harmony.one&quot;&gt;Harmony&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are aligned in their focus on empowering an equal and fair world. Doing good for the planet and humanity is at the core of both organizations’ DNA. Today, Harmony and ThreeFold are pleased to officially announce their collaborative partnership.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Harmony and ThreeFold will work together on developer and user projects on the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;grid_why&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;docs.harmony.one&#x2F;pangaea&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Pangaea&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;. Harmony’s developer community, and anyone interested in contributing to their Blockchain and being a validator within the Harmony staking ecosystem, is being invited to use a more decentralized, performant and affordable &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;cloud.threefold.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;Peer-to-Peer Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; solution brought by ThreeFold.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Developers can now deploy their nodes and any IT workloads on Pangaea and the ThreeFold Grid with an autonomous execution via &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;smart_contract&quot;&gt;Smart Contracts for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.  Anyone interested in being a node operator, as a validator, in the Harmony Blockchain using the ThreeFold Grid, is invited to get started in a few steps following this &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;setting-up-a-harmony-node-on-the-threefold-grid&#x2F;476&quot;&gt;documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
From ThreeFold Co-Founder Adnan Fatayerji,
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“We’re super excited about our partnership with Harmony. Their approach to decentralization of applications and transactions perfectly couples with our approach of trying to bring an inclusive Internet. Together we will form a big powerhouse for positive change in this world.”&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
ThreeFold and Harmony look forward to the further development of this collaboration.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-harmony&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#about-harmony&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: about-harmony&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;About Harmony&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;www.harmony.one&quot;&gt;Harmony&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a fast and open blockchain for decentralized applications. Its protocol has achieved secure and random state sharding, being the first sharded Proof of Stake on production. Harmony’s Mainnet supports thousands of nodes in multiple shards, producing blocks in a few seconds with instant finality. The network’s staking mechanism reduces centralization while supporting stake delegation, reward compounding and double-sign slashing. Harmony aims to build an open network of nodes operated and governed by a large community. Harmony has designed a novel Proof-of-Stake (PoS) mechanism for network security and economics - Effective Proof-of-Stake (EPoS) which reduces centralization and distributes rewards fairly to thousands of validators.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#about-threefold&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: about-threefold&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;About ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer Internet grid in the world.  They launched the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; V2.0 in  April 2020 – a  more performant, private &amp;amp; secure, affordable, and sustainable solution than centralized cloud and internet providers. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers (independent Internet capacity providers) around the globe, ThreeFold Grid - largest peer-to-peer Internet grid on earth, is now open for developers to build on top of it,  and users can now benefit from all the advantages of the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Foundation aims to empower a more equal, autonomous, decentralized,  and sustainable internet and does so  by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to individuals and creators, while incentivizing growth in developing regions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>DigiByte integrates with ThreeFold’s decentralized Grid</title>
		<published>2020-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-05-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/newsroom/digibyte-threefold/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/newsroom/digibyte-threefold/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;digibytefoundation.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;DigiByte Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;threefold.io&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Foundation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; are aligned – both focused on values, working towards their visions and missions in creating a truly decentralized, equal, and sustainable world that empowers humanity. Doing good for the planet is at the core of both organizations’ DNA. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Today, DigiByte and ThreeFold are pleased to officially announce their collaborative partnership.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
DigiByte and ThreeFold will work together on developer and user projects on the ThreeFold Grid. The DigiByte developer community, and anyone interested in contributing to the DigiByte Blockchain, is being invited to use a more decentralized and affordable cloud computing capacity. Developers can now deploy their DigiByte nodes and IT workloads on the ThreeFold Grid with an autonomous execution via &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;smart_contract&quot;&gt;Smart Contracts for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Further, community members are also being invited to explore possibilities in using the ThreeFold Grid’s capacity for their own personal computing needs and projects.  Anyone interested in being a node operator in the DigiByte Blockchain using the ThreeFold Grid would be highly encouraged to get started in a few steps following &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;how-to-deploy-a-digibyte-node-with-your-3bot-in-5-steps&#x2F;379&quot;&gt;the documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;br &#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold team is very proud to welcome The DigiByte Foundation to the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;consciousinternet.org&quot;&gt;Conscious Internet Alliance&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; initiative led by ThreeFold, where together with many other planet and human-centric projects, they will collaborate on making our global Internet neutral again. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-digibyte&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#about-digibyte&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: about-digibyte&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;About DigiByte:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;digibyte.io&#x2F;&quot;&gt;DigiByte&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; is a rapidly-growing open-source blockchain created in late 2013 and released in early 2014. After 6 years of forward-thinking development, DigiByte has become one of the safest, fastest, longest and most decentralized UTXO blockchain in existence with one of the most active communities in the Crypto and Blockchain space
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The DigiByte Foundation is a volunteer-managed organization that operates in a non-profit way. They protect and promote the true principles of decentralization and empower DigiByte and its community to establish and maintain a sustainable decentralized world. &lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#about-threefold&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: about-threefold&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;About ThreeFold:&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer Internet grid in the world.  They launched the ThreeFold Grid V2.0 in  April 2020 – a  more performant, private &amp;amp; secure, affordable, and sustainable solution than centralized cloud and internet providers. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers (independent Internet capacity providers) around the globe, the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;explorer.grid.tf&#x2F;&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;  is now open for developers to build on top of it,  and users can now benefit from all the advantages of the ThreeFold Grid.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Foundation aims to empower a more equal, autonomous (decentralized) and sustainable world, and does so  by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to the world, while incentivizing growth in developing regions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>TomoChain &amp; ThreeFold are joining forces to decentralize Cloud Computing</title>
		<published>2020-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-05-20T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/newsroom/tomochain-threefold/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/newsroom/tomochain-threefold/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-week-marks-a-big-step-in-the-history-of-tomochain-and-threefold-as-both-organizations-join-forces-to-work-towards-a-common-vision-of-a-more-sustainable-and-decentralized-world-the-threefold-grid-s-peer-to-peer-nature-comes-with-many-advantages-for-blockchains-as-it-truly-decentralizes-their-it-infrastructures-and-enabling-better-performance-security-affordability-and-sustainability-as-compared-to-current-centralized-cloud-alternatives-tomochain-will-invite-their-developer-community-and-anyone-interested-in-contributing-to-the-tomochain-blockchain-to-connect-and-use-the-threefold-grid-by-deploying-their-masternodes-and-workloads-on-the-threefold-grid-their-developers-will-benefit-from-a-more-decentralized-and-affordable-cloud-offering-and-benefit-from-the-autonomous-execution-of-their-workloads-via-threefold-s-smart-contract-for-it-anyone-interested-in-being-part-of-the-tomochain-node-ecosystem-using-the-threefold-grid-would-be-highly-encouraged-to-get-started-in-a-few-steps-following-the-documentation-furthermore-with-the-recent-announcement-of-tomochain-s-dex-protocol-tomox-released-both-organizations-will-also-test-the-threefold-p2p-cloud-solution-to-enable-developers-to-build-dexs-on-top-of-tomochain-using-threefold-s-truly-decentralized-it-infrastructure&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#this-week-marks-a-big-step-in-the-history-of-tomochain-and-threefold-as-both-organizations-join-forces-to-work-towards-a-common-vision-of-a-more-sustainable-and-decentralized-world-the-threefold-grid-s-peer-to-peer-nature-comes-with-many-advantages-for-blockchains-as-it-truly-decentralizes-their-it-infrastructures-and-enabling-better-performance-security-affordability-and-sustainability-as-compared-to-current-centralized-cloud-alternatives-tomochain-will-invite-their-developer-community-and-anyone-interested-in-contributing-to-the-tomochain-blockchain-to-connect-and-use-the-threefold-grid-by-deploying-their-masternodes-and-workloads-on-the-threefold-grid-their-developers-will-benefit-from-a-more-decentralized-and-affordable-cloud-offering-and-benefit-from-the-autonomous-execution-of-their-workloads-via-threefold-s-smart-contract-for-it-anyone-interested-in-being-part-of-the-tomochain-node-ecosystem-using-the-threefold-grid-would-be-highly-encouraged-to-get-started-in-a-few-steps-following-the-documentation-furthermore-with-the-recent-announcement-of-tomochain-s-dex-protocol-tomox-released-both-organizations-will-also-test-the-threefold-p2p-cloud-solution-to-enable-developers-to-build-dexs-on-top-of-tomochain-using-threefold-s-truly-decentralized-it-infrastructure&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: this-week-marks-a-big-step-in-the-history-of-tomochain-and-threefold-as-both-organizations-join-forces-to-work-towards-a-common-vision-of-a-more-sustainable-and-decentralized-world-the-threefold-grid-s-peer-to-peer-nature-comes-with-many-advantages-for-blockchains-as-it-truly-decentralizes-their-it-infrastructures-and-enabling-better-performance-security-affordability-and-sustainability-as-compared-to-current-centralized-cloud-alternatives-tomochain-will-invite-their-developer-community-and-anyone-interested-in-contributing-to-the-tomochain-blockchain-to-connect-and-use-the-threefold-grid-by-deploying-their-masternodes-and-workloads-on-the-threefold-grid-their-developers-will-benefit-from-a-more-decentralized-and-affordable-cloud-offering-and-benefit-from-the-autonomous-execution-of-their-workloads-via-threefold-s-smart-contract-for-it-anyone-interested-in-being-part-of-the-tomochain-node-ecosystem-using-the-threefold-grid-would-be-highly-encouraged-to-get-started-in-a-few-steps-following-the-documentation-furthermore-with-the-recent-announcement-of-tomochain-s-dex-protocol-tomox-released-both-organizations-will-also-test-the-threefold-p2p-cloud-solution-to-enable-developers-to-build-dexs-on-top-of-tomochain-using-threefold-s-truly-decentralized-it-infrastructure&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;&lt;em&gt;This week marks a big step in the history of TomoChain and ThreeFold as both organizations join forces to work towards a common vision of a more sustainable and decentralized world.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;grid_why&quot;&gt;ThreeFold Grid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;’s peer-to-peer nature comes with many advantages for blockchains as it truly decentralizes their IT infrastructures and, enabling better performance, security, affordability, and sustainability, as compared to current centralized cloud alternatives.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;tomochain.com&quot;&gt;TomoChain&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; will invite their developer community and anyone interested in contributing to the TomoChain Blockchain, to connect and use the Threefold Grid. By deploying their Masternodes and workloads on the ThreeFold Grid, their developers will benefit from a more decentralized and affordable cloud offering and benefit from the autonomous execution of their workloads via ThreeFold’s &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;smart_contract&quot;&gt;Smart Contract for IT&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Anyone interested in being part of the TomoChain node ecosystem using the ThreeFold Grid would be highly encouraged to get started in a few steps &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;forum.threefold.io&#x2F;t&#x2F;setting-up-a-tomochain-node-in-5-steps&#x2F;389&quot;&gt;following the documentation&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Furthermore, with the recent announcement of TomoChain’s DEX Protocol, TomoX, released, both organizations will also test the &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;sdk&#x2F;#&#x2F;intro&quot;&gt;ThreeFold P2P Cloud&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; solution to enable developers to build DEXs on top of TomoChain using ThreeFold’s truly decentralized IT infrastructure.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-tomochain&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#about-tomochain&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: about-tomochain&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;About Tomochain&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TomoChain is a scalable blockchain, powered via Proof-of-Stake Voting consensus and used commercially by companies globally. The TomoChain blockchain and product ecosystem enable the development of high-performance blockchain projects that focus on decentralizing finance. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Their products include (1) a fast &amp;amp; near-zero Fees: 2000 TPS, 2-second block-time, and EVM  compatible, and (2) an array of original features and protocols designed to support speed, privacy, usability, and liquidity needs all in one platform. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
After a successful ICO in 2018, Tomochain experienced an incredible growth last year to become one of the most reputed blockchains of South East Asia, and globally. They now focus on their mission to accelerate the onboarding of millions of users by empowering today’s applications with technology that masks the friction of Blockchain, all while retaining its underlying benefits.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-threefold&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#about-threefold&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: about-threefold&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;About ThreeFold&lt;&#x2F;h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ThreeFold has developed the largest and most advanced peer-to-peer Internet grid in the world.  They launched the ThreeFold Grid V2.0 in  April 2020 - a  more performant, private &amp;amp; secure, affordable, and sustainable solution than centralized cloud and internet providers. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
With a collective and incentivized ecosystem of Farmers (independent Internet capacity providers) around the globe, the ThreeFold Grid is now open for developers to build on top of it and benefit from all the advantages that comes with it.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Foundation aims to empower a more equal, autonomous (decentralized) and sustainable world, and does so  by providing the necessary peer-to-peer technologies and infrastructure to the world, while incentivizing growth in developing regions.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>An Intro to the ThreeFold Token</title>
		<published>2020-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2020-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/intro-to-the-tf-token/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/intro-to-the-tf-token/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Token is the currency of the new Internet. It is a decentralized digital currency that represents a unit of reservation of capacity (compute, storage) on the largest peer-to-peer network of capacity on earth.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Capacity is a new high-demand market, and the TFT will be the medium of exchange for this commodity on the peer-to-peer internet brought by ThreeFold. TFT synergistically connects the world of cloud and blockchain markets to the most scalable universal substrate without compromising, performance, security and privacy.
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-are-threefold-tokens-created&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#how-are-threefold-tokens-created&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: how-are-threefold-tokens-created&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;How are ThreeFold Tokens created?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No ThreeFold Tokens have ever been minted. ThreeFold Tokens are generated through a process called “Farming”. Farming happens when active internet capacity is added to the ThreeFold Grid. Independent farmers earn ThreeFold Tokens (TFT) by providing neutral and decentralized internet capacity, thus expending the usable Grid. Therefore no central entity controls the internet.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-good-reasons-to-buy-threefold-tokens&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#5-good-reasons-to-buy-threefold-tokens&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: 5-good-reasons-to-buy-threefold-tokens&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;5 good reasons to buy ThreeFold Tokens&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TFTs are exclusively generated when new capacity is added to the TF Grid. There are no centralized issuers. Tokens have not been created out of thin air.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;While the ThreeFold Grid can expand, a maximum of 4 Billion TFTs can ever be in circulation. This limit ensures stability of value and incentivization for all stakeholders.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TFT lives on the Stellar Blockchain. TFT holders benefit from a big ecosystem of proven wallets and mediums of exchange.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By employing Stellar technology, TFT transactions and smart contracts are powered by one of the most energy-efficient blockchains available. Furthermore, TFT is the medium of exchange on the greenest internet network in the world.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The market for farming, cultivating and trading TFT is open to all. Anyone with internet connection, power supply and necessary hardware can become a Farmer or trade ThreeFold tokens (TFT).&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;By buying, holding, and utilizing ThreeFold Tokens, you are actively supporting the expansion of the ThreeFold Grid and its use cases — creating a more sustainable, fair, and equally accessible Internet.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;To learn more about the token, please dive into &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;token&quot;&gt;our wiki&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Important note: TFTs are not an investment instrument. It is the medium of exchange on the ThreeFold Grid, and is a mechanism to enable the Internet we believe is possible.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
	<entry xml:lang="en">
		<title>Co-create the new Internet. Participate with TFT!</title>
		<published>2019-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
		<updated>2019-06-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
		<link href="https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/tft-on-liquid-and-btcalpha/" type="text/html"/>
		<id>https://threefoldfoundation.github.io/www_threefold_io/blog/tft-on-liquid-and-btcalpha/</id>
		<content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;do-you-believe-that-the-world-needs-change&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#do-you-believe-that-the-world-needs-change&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: do-you-believe-that-the-world-needs-change&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Do you believe that the world needs change?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you believe in decentralization? Equality? Sustainability?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
Do you believe in circular economies, where everyone is invited to partake and succeed?
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The ThreeFold Token is the currency of the new Internet and brings true solutions to all the above questions. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
It supports the ThreeFold Foundation - an open ecosystem that is shaping a better world by empowering game-changing technology. ThreeFold is growing a green and conscious peer-to-peer Internet that is available everywhere and owned by everyone – across geographical and cultural borders, empowering people to be autonomous, and providing equal chances to learn, partake and succeed.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;ready-to-support-a-new-internet&quot;&gt;&lt;a class=&quot;zola-anchor&quot; href=&quot;#ready-to-support-a-new-internet&quot; aria-label=&quot;Anchor link for: ready-to-support-a-new-internet&quot;&gt;🔗&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;Ready to support a new Internet?&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By buying and holding TFT, anyone can support the ThreeFold Foundation’s ability to achieve its next technological and growth milestones (see &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;tdeoverview&quot;&gt;Token Distribution Event&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; for use-cases). From funding the next technological innovations to supporting the growth of ThreeFold use-cases built on top of the ThreeFold Grid, TFT powers the expansion of the new Internet. 
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
The time has come for us to step up and shape the world we believe is possible. Join us and lets co-create our futures together.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Get TFT on &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;app.liquid.com&#x2F;exchange&#x2F;TFTBTC&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; now.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Get TFT on &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;btc-alpha.com&#x2F;en&#x2F;exchange&#x2F;TFT_BTC&quot;&gt;BTC-Alpha&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; now.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
On behalf of our planet, humanity and the ThreeFold Community, we thank you for considering empowering a better world.
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;
&lt;br&#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you need more guidance on buying TFT, please head &lt;a rel=&quot;nofollow noreferrer&quot; href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;library.threefold.me&#x2F;info&#x2F;tfgrid&#x2F;#&#x2F;how_to_buy&quot;&gt;here&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;em&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
	</entry>
</feed>
